本字幕由志愿者义务贡献，采用许可协议
知识共享 署名-非商业性使用-相同方式共享 3.0 美国
Stanford University. >> All right, well,
斯坦福大学
welcome to Lecture 5 then of CS193P this Fall of 2017.
欢迎参加 2017 年秋季学期斯坦福 CS193P 的第五节课
So I'm gonna take just a few minutes of the beginning here
我会在这节课的开始花上几分钟来
to go over just a couple of more little Swift things.
讲讲更多的关于 Swift 的知识
These are actually in your reading assignment for
它们实际上是在你们这周的阅读任务中的
this week. So I'm really just kinda emphasizing these
因此我只会强调一下这些东西
things, then we're gonna dive into our main topic today
接着我们就会进入我们今天的主题的学习
which is views, drawings, how you do custom drawing in iOS.
那就是视图和画图（views, drawings）如何在 iOS 上画东西
And I'm gonna start with a huge demo, the only thing I'm
并且我会写一个非常大的示例程序
gonna probably be able to do today is the model of our MVC.
我今天应该只能写完我们 MVC 中的模型（Model）
But that's gonna allow me to show you an example of enum,
我可以用这个来给你们看看枚举类型的例子
which we didn't get to work into concentration.
我们没有在 Concentration 中使用枚举类型
So you only theoretically know enum, and we'll be actually do
所以你们只是在理论上熟悉枚举类型，我们这节课会
enum. All right, so let's do these little minor things.
实际使用枚举类型。让我们开始这些小块知识的学习
One of them is error handling in Swift.
其中一个是 Swift 的错误处理（error handling）
Now, a lot of times you'll have an error and
很多时候你会得到一个错误
it will be something that kind of, could be expected or
而这些错误在某种意义上是可以被预测的
anticipated. You know, you do something over the network and
比如说，你用网络做些是什么
there might be a network time out,
你可能就会得到连接超时的错误
that's kind of a normal error.
这是非常常见的错误
If you have that kind of error, you likely would have
如果你得到了这样的错误，你可能会
an argument to the function that goes and
向这个函数中传入一个参数
does that network call. Maybe it's even a closure that calls
并且让它来负责网络的调用，那个参数甚至可以是一个闭包
you back and said, I found this somewhat expected error.
它返回并说，我找到了这个预计的错误
But sometimes you have errors that you don't expect or
但有的时候你会有一些你没有预料的的错误
that are kind of rare, and really disrupt the usage of
或者一些很罕见的错误，它们可能会中断一个函数的调用
a method or whatever. And in that kind of error,
或者其他什么。对于这样的错误
instead of having to have one of your arguments be an error
我们不需要用我们的一个参数作为错误处理器
handler or returning an error, or something like that.
或者说返回一个错误，或其他类似的做法
You can do something that's called throwing an error.
你可以直接抛出（throw）一个错误
Now, in other languages,
在其他语言中
you might think of this as like raising exceptions or
你可能会认为这就是抛出一个异常
something like that. It's a little simpler and
或其他类似的东西，但在 Swift 编程中
more elegant when you design in Swift. It's as simple as
这会更加的简单优雅。它就像这样
this, a method that could get an error, okay,
一样简单：一个可能会得到一个错误的函数
a significant error that would disrupt what it's doing,
这个错误可能会打断我们正在执行的任务
can decide that it throws errors. And you see these
而可能得到错误的函数可以选择要抛出这个错误
methods very clearly because when they're declared, they'll
你可以很简单地辨别出这些函数，因为当它们被声明时
have the word throws at the end. So this function save
它们的末尾会有 throws 关键字，那么这样的函数
throws. Okay, if it gets an error, it throws this error.
会保存 throws，如果它得到了一个错误，它会抛出那个错误
Now, when it throws an error at you, you need to catch it.
那么，当它抛出一个错误的时候，你需要接住（catch）它
Okay, and you catch this error and
当你接住错误后
then you can look at it and decide what to do. So
你可以看看它是啥，并且决定要做什么
how do you catch an error that has thrown? Well,
那么，你要如何接住函数抛出的错误呢？
you do that by putting this do catch construct around your
你可以通过将这个 do catch 结构
call to the method that might throw. And you say, try, in
放在那个可能会抛出错误的函数的旁边
front of the call. So you're going to try this method
并且在函数调用前使用 try 关键字，这样表示你会试着调用这个函数
that it might throw. But since you've put it inside this do,
但它可能会抛出错误，但因为你一进将这个调用放在了这个 do catch 中
catch thing, that thing you see up there, you're going to
就像我们幻灯片里写的那个
catch that error. Okay, so it's as simple as that.
你会去接住那个错误，就是这么简单
So, any method that throws has to be called with try.
所有可能会抛出错误的函数必须要用 try 来调用
Okay, you have to let Swift know I understand that this
你要让 Swift 知道你了解这个函数可能会抛出错误
can throw, and so I'm trying it.
所以你正在尝试调用它
But it doesn't necessarily have to be kept, caught,
但实际上那个被抛出的错误不一定必须要被接住
and I'll show you in a second how to do it without catching.
等一下我就给你们展示如何不接住那个错误
If you do wanna catch, then you do this do catch, and
如果你想要接住错误，你就要用这个 do catch 结构
in the catch you notice there's the green, let error.
并注意到在 catch 部分的代码中有一段绿色的 let error
Okay, that little error thing, it's just a local variable.
这个 error 它就是一个局部变量
That's the thing that gets thrown at you, okay,
它就是那个函数抛出来的错误时
when it throws an error. And it's going to be
所抛出的错误，而这个 error 是实现了
something that implements the protocol error, but
Error 这个协议的
there's actually nothing in that protocol.
但实际上那个协议中什么都没有
It just identifies, it's just typing this thing as error.
它只是用来确认这个东西的类型是 Error
Now, in iOS when things, errors gets thrown at you,
在 iOS 中，当你得到错误的时候
there almost always going to be NSErrors.
那些错误绝大多数都会是 NSError
So an NSError is just a class, it implements the Error
NSError 是一个实现了 Error 协议的一个类
protocol which is to say that, that nothing in particular.
Error 这个协议并没有做什么
But NSError has a lot of nice methods and vars,
但是 NSError 这个类中有许多有用的函数和变量
like the error code, even a localized description of
比如说错误代码，它甚至有本地化的错误描述
the error that you could present to a user,
你可以直接将这个本地化的错误描述呈现给用户
for example. So the way this goes is if you had a function
那么如果你有一个
save that throws,
可以抛出错误地函数
you're gonna go looking in its documentation and
你要去看看文档并
see what kind of NSError stuff it can throw. And it'll throw
确定哪些类型的 NSError 是它能抛出的，它可能会抛出
certain errors like save, the save maybe it's for
一些特定类型的错误，比如对于 save 函数
saving into a database and the disk is full, so the database
它可能想要向数据库保存数据，但我们的磁盘已经满了
couldn't save so maybe there's an error code for
因此数据库无法保存，那么这里就可能会有一个关于
disk full or whatever. So this is what you do if you want to
磁盘已满的错误，或其他什么。那么这就是你如何
catch a thrown error and kind of handle it, look at it,
接住一个被抛出的错误，并且处理它
see what it is, decide what to do. But you can just say,
看看它是啥，决定要做什么。但你也可以只写
try!, and what that means is, try this and
try! 这就意味着，尝试调用这个函数
if it throws crash my app. Now,
如果它抛出一个错误，那就让我的程序崩溃
you would only do this if you were 100% certain that,
你们应当只在你们 100% 确定
that thing could not throw in the circumstance that you're
在你们调用这个函数的情境下，它不会抛出错误
doing, which is extremely rare, so we rarely do try!.
才能这样做。这种情况很少见，我们很少会用 try!
But a better one if you don't care about the error is try?.
如果你不关心它抛出的错误是什么，一个更好的方法是用 try?
So try?, means please try this and if it throws, don't crash,
try? 意味着请尝试调用它，如果它抛出了错误，不要崩溃
but just ignore the fact that it threw. So
但也无视它抛出的错误
this is kind of like try and
这就有点像尝试调用
ignore. Now the interesting thing is, you might be calling
并无视错误。而有趣的是，你可能会调用
a function that returns a value. An int that can throw.
一个有返回值的函数，比如说返回一个整形，而这个函数还会抛出错误
So here I've got my error prone function that returns
这里我有这个函数，它会返回一个整形
an int, okay, and so what if I wanna try it with try?. Well,
那么如果我在这里使用 try? 来调用它
if it succeeds, I need that int back. But if it fails,
如果没有错误，我要取得那个整形的值，但如果它失败了
I can't get the int back. So what happens when you do try?,
我无法取得那个整形的值，那么当你用 try? 的时候会发生什么
it changes the return value essentially, of the function
它实际上改变了这个函数的返回值类型
to be an optional version of that value. So
改成了这个函数的返回值类型的可选类型
if you have an error prone function returns an int and
那么如果你有这里这个返回整形的函数
you try? it, and you let it equal something, you know,
并且用 try? 调用它，接着赋值给某个变量
let x equal that. This x now becomes an optional int,
比如说 let x = 那个函数，那么 x 的类型就变成了可选的整形
because if it throws, it's gonna give you
因为如果那个函数抛出了错误
nil. If it doesn't throw, you'll get the normal x value
它会返回 nil 如果它没有抛出错误，x 就是正常
that error prone function that returns an int, returns. Okay?
的那个函数的整形返回值
So that's error handling. There's not a lot of methods
那么这就是错误处理，在 iOS 中并不是有
that throw in iOS there, in there occasionally. You know,
许多的函数会抛出错误，有时
you might have a typical app, maybe you have three or
你可能会有个特定的程序中有一些这样的抛出
four of them, somewhere. They're fairly rare but
错误的函数。它们比较少见
you got to know how to handle them. So these are the ways to
但你也要知道该如何处理它们，就是通过我们刚刚讲到的方法
handle them. All right, I wanna circle back now to Any.
好的，那么让我们现在回去讲 Any
This type Any that we saw with
这个 Any 类型
NSAttributedString dictionary. There's another one called any
我们曾在 NSAttributedString dictionary 中见过。还有一个类型叫做
object which is exact the same as Any, it's just for classes
AnyObject，它和 Any 是完全一样的，只是它只能用于
only, and the object is the any of classes only. And
类，AnyObject 是 Any 的类的表达
I told you that Any means, you don't know what type it is,
我讲过，Any 意味着你不知道这个类型是什么
it could be any type. And we also know that that's not
它可以是任意的类型，并且我们也知道
very Swifty, and cuz Swift is strongly tight. So Any and
它不是很符合 Swift 的风格，因为 Swift 是一个强类型语言
AnyObject are in there for compatible with Objective-C.
AnyObject 只是为了能与 Objective-C 兼容
Objective-C had a very important type called ID which
Objective-C 中有一个非常重要的类型叫做 ID
was essentially any and it was built in to all of the APIs.
它本质上就是 Any，并且它被写入了所有的 API 中
So when Swift came along and tried to be strongly typed,
所以当 Swift 要成为强类型语言
it had to have this one concession. So
它必须要做这个让步
we don't use as I've said, any in our own code, it's for
我们不会再我们自己的代码中用到 Any
backwards compatibility. So variables of type any could
它只是用来向后兼容的。Any 类型的变量可以
hold any type. Structs, enums, classes, anything.
保存任何类型，结构体，枚举类型，类，任何类型都可以
And the problem though is, you can't send any messages to
而问题是你不能向 Any 类型的对象
something of type Any, because you don't, in your code,
传递信息，因为在你的代码中，你不知道它具体
know what it is. Okay? Now, Swift, under the covers,
是什么类型，Swift 知道
might know what it is, but since you've typed it Any,
它是什么类型的，但因为你将它设置为 Any 类型
it's assuming you don't want to send any messages to it
Swift 会假设你不想向它传递任何消息
that you don't know what it is. So, how do we
因为你不知道它是什么。那么，我们如何
deal with that case in Swift where we got the strongly type
在 Swift 这种强类型语言中处理这种
language, we can't send a message to Any. Well,
情况呢，我们现在无法向 Any 传递信息
we got to convert it. Now, let's talk about where you're
实际上，我们需要转变（convert）它，我们先讲讲你们会在哪里
gonna see it, you already saw it in NSAttributedString case,
碰到 Any，你们已经在 NSAttibutedString 中见过 Any
right? Well, we have that dictionary.
我们有那个字典类型
Another place you will see it is arguments to methods. So
另外一个你们会用到 Any 的地方是在函数的参数
here is a method called prepare for
这有个函数叫做 prepare(for segue)
segue. It's a UIView controller method, right?
它是一个在 UIViewController 中的函数
You all know what a UIView controller is?
大家都知道 UIViewController 是什么吧
We made one for concentration. And
我们在 Concentration 中写了一个
I talked about when we do MVCs and we have multiple MVCs, and
我们在我们将多 MVC 的时候讲到当我们有多个 MVC
they own a whole screen. Well, we sometimes transition from
并且它们各自拥有自己的屏幕的时候，我们有时需要从一个
one MVC together, to another. And this prepare for segue,
MVC 跳到另一个 MVC，而这个 prepare(for segue)
a segue is a transition from one MVC to the other, this
一个 segue 就是从一个 MVC 到另一个 MVC 的跳转
gets called in a view control when transition happens. Well,
当跳转发生的时候，这个在对应的 ViewController 的 prepare 函数就会被调用
one of the arguments to it there at the end is sender of
而它的最后的那个参数就是 Any? 类型的 sender
type Any?. Okay, an optional Any. And that's basically
一个可选类型的 Any，它代表的就是
what button cause this MVC transfer to a new MVC so.
使得从一个 MVC 到另一个 MVC 跳转发生的那个按钮
So it could well be a button that, that sender is but
那么这个 sender 可以是一个按钮
it can also happen if you click on a row in a table
但是，这个跳转也可能在你点击一个 UITableView 的一行的时候
view. So that's not a button, that's a table view. Cell,
发生，这种情况下，sender 就不是按钮了，它应该是一个 UITableViewCell
okay, or it could happen from something else.
这个跳转也可能从其他地方发生
It could even happen by code, in which case this is a nil.
甚至可能是由代码直接命令执行的，在这种情况下 sender 应该是 nil
So that's why you need Any right there, because you're
因此你在这里要用到 Any，因为你不确定
not sure whether it was a button or a table view cell or
是一个 UIButton 还是 UITableViewCell 还是
something else that caused this thing to happen. So
其他什么让这个跳转发生的
you'll see it as arguments, a case very rarely to a function
所以你有时会看到一个函数的参数
like this where you can kinda pass anything in there,. But
就像这样，我们可以向它传递任意的参数
how are we gonna use this Any stuff? Okay, let's say
但是我们要如何使用这个 Any 类型的变量呢
a button was passed on your table, how do I know what it
比如说一个按钮或者一个列表视图被传来进来
is and talk to it, and all that when it's this Any thing.
我该如何知道它是什么并且向它传递信息呢
Okay, before I show you how to do it, of course don't use Any
在向你们展示该怎么做之前，请不要在这门课中使用 Any
in this course except for to do backwards compatible call
除非你要做向后兼容或者调用
APIs. You don't have your own data structures would not be
API，你在你自己的数据类型中
use Any. Some people try to use Any when
不要使用 Any，有的人在不知道该如何设计
they basically don't know how to design a data structure,
数据类型的时候就简单地使用 Any
and they're like, I'll just make this an Any,
他们就想，我直接把这个变量设为 Any就好了
an array of Any and
一个 Any 类型的数组
I'll just start throwing random things in there.
这样就可以向数组中存任何东西了
No, we don't do that, okay, that's not, Swift. All right,
我们不会这么做，这不是 Swift 的风格
so now how do I use Any. I have to convert it to a type
那么该如何使用 Any 呢，我必须要将它转变为一个
that I do know, since I can't send any messages or vars,
我认识的类型，因为我不能向它传递任何函数或者变量
I have to convert it. And we convert it,
我必须要转变它。而我们通过
with a special keyword and Swift called as,
一个 Swift 中的特殊的关键字，叫做 as 来转变它
as question mark. And what as does, is it just tries to
as? 它做的就是尝试转变那个 Any 类型变量
convert that any to the type you specify and if it can't,
为你指定的那个类型，如果它不能转变的话
it returns a nil. That's why it's as question mark.
就返回 nil，因此它是 as 后面接问号
And it's as simple as that. So here's an example,
就这么简单，这有一个例子
it's best learn by example here.
我们最后通过例子来学习
Let's say, I have a var called unknown, which of type Any, so
加入我有一个叫做 unknown 的变量，它是 Any 类型的
I don't know what's in it. It could be anything in there,
我不知道它里面装的是什么，它可以装任何东西
and I think that that thing in unknown might be of type,
而我觉得 unknown 的类型可能是
MyType. I'm not sure but I think it might be MyType.
MyType，我不确定，我我觉得它有可能是 MyType
So I'm gonna say if I can let foo, which is a new variable,
那么我只用写如果我可以 let foo，foo 是一个新的变量
equal unknown as MyType. Then inside there,
let foo = unknown as? MyType 那么在那里
I can send messages to foo that MyType understands,
我可以向 foo 传递 MyType 可以理解的信息
right? So I've just converted unknown into
所以我就是将unknown 转变为了一个新的
a new variable of type MyType, if possible by using as.
MyType 类型的变量，通过使用 as 关键字
And you can see this is nice, it reads like English.
你们可以发现这很棒，读起来就像英语一样
If I can let foo equal unknown as MyType,
如果我可以让 foo 等于 MyType 类型的 unknown
then I'm going to use it as MyType. So that's it,
那么我就接着以 MyType 类型来使用它
it's very simple, that's how we access Any. And
就是这么简单，这就是我们使用 Any 的方法
if it wasn't, if unknown was of some other type and
如果它不是，如果 unknown 是其他什么类型
couldn't be interpreted as MyType,
而不能被转变为 MyType
then this the curly braces, that stuff doesn't happen.
那么这段大括号中的代码就不会被执行
You could even say else, and something else, and
你甚至可以用 else，那么
something else would happen, that would be fine too.
else 中的代码就会被执行
Now this casting of As is not just for
而这个 as 所做的转变
Any, we can also cast other things. Why, why else would we
不仅适用于 Any，它也可以用来做其他类型的转变，为什么
ever want to cast? Well one classic one to cast, is to
我们想要做转变呢，一个很经典转变就是
cast from the variable type to one of its subclasses. So
将一个变量的类型转变为这个类型的子类的类型
let's look an example of that. So here I have a variable vc,
让我们来看看这个的一个例子，我们这有一个叫做 vc 的变量
very importantly it's of type UIViewController.
值得注意的是它的类型是 UIViewController
In other words the iOS class, UIViewController that's
这个 UIViewController 是 iOS 中的一个类
the type of vc. Now I'm setting it equal to creating
它是 vc 的类型。接着我将 vc 赋值为
a ConcentrationViewController, which is a subclass, let's
一个新建的 ConcentrationViewController 假设这是
say, of UIViewController. Now the type vc,
UIViewController 的一个子类
even though I assign to it a ConcentrationViewController,
那么尽管我将 vc 赋值为 ConcentrationViewController
that type is still UIViewController not
它的类型仍然是 UIViewController
ConcentrationViewController. That's not its type,
而不是 ConcentrationViewController
its type is UIViewController. But this is a legal statement,
它的类型是 UIViewController，这是一个合法的声明
because of course a ConcentrationViewController
因为 ConcentrationViewController
inherits from UIViewController, and that is
继承了 UIViewController
a UIViewController. Now if I wanted to send flipCard,
因此它是一个 UIViewController，那么现在如果我想传递
lets say that was a method in ConcentrationViewController,
flipCard，假设它是 ConcentrationViewController 中的一个函数
to vc I could not do that. It would not even compile, why?
将 flipCard 传递给 vc，我不能这么做，这甚至不会通过编译
Because vc is subtype UIViewController, and
因为 vc 的类型是 UIViewController
the class UIViewController doesn't have flipCard.
而 UIViewController 这个类没有 flipCard 这个函数
ConcentrationViewController has it, but
ConcentrationViewController 中才有
not UIViewController. So people get confused about
但 UIViewController 中没有，所以人们会对此感到困惑
this, it's kind of like back when we're talking about
就像我们之前讲的
the protocols and I had things to move.
协议，我有 thingsToMove
And it was of type movable, and I had a car in there and
它的类型是 moveable，并有一个这个类型的变量 car
I want it to send a change oil and people were like, why not?
我想将调用它其中的函数 changeOil，人们可能会觉得这是可以的
Well, because the variable was typed to be a movable, and
但这是不行的，因为这个变量的类型是 moveable
movables didn't know how to change oil, cars do.
而 moveable 并不知道如何实现 changeOil，car 类型才知道
This is the same kind of thing here, exactly the same thing
就和这里的东西是一个意思，完全一个意思
just with inheritance instead of protocols. So
这里只是继承的关系，而不是协议间的关系
what if I did wanna send flipCard to vc, how
那么如果我想将 flipCard 传递给 vc 呢
would I do it? Well, I can cast with any in exact same way?
我该怎么做呢？我可以像转变 Any 类型一样转变它
I can say, if I let some new variable called cvc,
我可以写 if let cvc = vc as?
ConcentrationViewController equal the vc
cvc 的是 ConcentrationViewController 的缩写
as a ConentrationViewController.
if let cvc = vc as? ConcentrationViewController
Now cvc is a ConcentrationViewController,
那么现在 cvc 就是一个 ConcentrationViewController
I can send it flipCard. So same way I did with Any,
我可以向它传递 flipCard，和我们对 Any 类型做得一样
I'm checking to see if it's possible for
我正在确定这个变量是否
this var to be converted, in this case downcasted.
可以被转变，在这个例子中我们叫它向下转变(downcast)
This is called downcasted, to a subclass of that thing, so
这个叫做向下转变(downcast)，就是转变成那个类型的子类
I can interact with it as that subclass. Same thing
这样我就可以将它当做它的子类的类型使用它
happen here with protocols, we could do that same thing with
在这里，协议也是一样的，我们可以对 moveabl 类型
the car in the movable. We could had a movable var and
的 car 变量做同样的事，我们可以尝试将一个moveable
try to cast it as a car. And if you were successful,
类型的变量并尝试将它转变为 car 类型的变量，如果这成功了
then we can send a change oil. But if it was a shape and
那么我就可以将 changeOil 传递给它，但如果它是一个 shape 类型
that failed, we would return nil and
而这失败了，这就会返回 nil
we would not be able to do it. So
并且我们就我发这么做了
you're gonna see us doing this casting not as much with Any,
那么你们可以看到我们并不一定只对 Any 类型进行转变
some with Any, but a lot of time just down casting.
我们多数情况下是进行向下转变
Because we have some function that takes some super class
因为我们会有一些函数接收一个父类作为参数
and we pass a down cast subclass into it.
我们向他传递一个父类
And we're gonna down cast it to look at the subclass
接着我们试着将它转变为它的子类
in case it is that subclass, then we can send it messages.
如果转换成功了，我们就可以向它传递信息了
All right, so that's it for
好的，Any 和转变对象
Any and Castings object.
就讲到这里
The last last slide that I have here before we dive in to
我们学习视图前的最后
views, is just four other interesting classes that
一页幻灯片是讲其他有趣的类
you should know about in foundation. One is NSObject.
这些类在 Foundation 中，一个是 NSObject
NSObject is the root class of all classes from
NSObject 是所有来自 Objective-C 的类的
Objective-C. All the things like UIViewController,
根类，所有的类，像 UIViewController
all the UI kit classes, all those things that were
所有在 UIKit 中的类，所有我们在
developed in the Objective-C world, and
Objective-C 开发的类
are compatible still with Objective-C. Their root class,
它们都与 Objective-C 兼容，而它们的根类
the thing they inherit from eventually at the top,
就是它们所继承的最顶层的类
is NSObject. In Swift, no requirement to subclass from
是 NSObject，在 Swift 的类中不一定要继承
NSObject, although there's a few tiny esoteric APIs that
NSObject 但是有一小部分的 API 会
ask you to pass a class in, that has to implement
要求你传递一个实现了 NSObject 的类作为参数
NSObject. And I'll explain them to you when we get to it,
当我们用到它们的时候我会再给你们解释
but normally your Swift class, like remember concentration
但通常来说，你的 Swift 的类，就像是 Concentration
that class, we originally made it. It didn't inherit from
这个类，我们在开始的时候写的它，它没有继承
NSObject. It didn't inherit from anything.
NSObject，它没有继承任何东西
When it was a class, we converted it to struct later.
我们之后还将它转变成了一个类
And that's perfectly legal in Swift,
这在 Swift 中是完全合法的
that was not true in Objective-C.
但在 Objective-C 中并不是这样的
In Objective-C pretty much all classes had to inherit
在 Objective-C 中基本上所有的类都要
from NSObject, because some of the runtime was built into
继承 NSObject，因为有些运行时是被写入这个
this class rather than being in the actual runtime like it
类中的，而不是像在 Swift 中一样真正的运行时
is in Swift. Okay, second interesting class is NSNumber,
好的，第二个有趣的类是 NSNumber
in Objective-C when you pass numbers around you actually
在 Objective-C 中当你传递数字的时候
pass them with this class.
你实际上是用的这个类
NSNumber, it's a class so it's a reference type.
NSNumber，它是一个类，因此它是一个引用类型
You didn't have double and int as classes.
在 Objective-C 中没有 Double 或者 Int 类
You had C like doubles and ints in Objective-C, but
Objective-C 中的 Double 和 Int 类型是 C 风格的
you didn't have that. So if you wanted to pass something
Objective-C 没有 Double 类，所以当你想要传递数据
in an object oriented way, you had to pass this NSNumnber.
以面向对象的方式传递的话，你必须要传递这个 NSNumber
Now it can represent any kind of number, floating point
它可以代表任意类型的数字，浮点类型(floating point)
number, integer, anything. It's a kind of a generic
整形，任何类型，它有点像
number holder, even a boolean it can hold in there.
泛型的数字保存器，甚至布尔类型也可以保存在它里面
Now it's really awesome is all the API throughout iOS that
而很酷的一点是 iOS 中的所有接收 NSNumber
takes an NSNumber and there's a lot of it, automatically
的 API，这有很多，它们都会自动地
bridged to the Swift types. So if you have an Objective-C
将它桥接到 Swift 中的对应的类型。如果你在 iOS 中
based API somewhere in iOS that takes a number as
有一个基于 Objective-C的 API，它接收一个数字作为参数
an argument, you can pass a double in there. Or an int, or
那么你可以向它传递一个 Double 类型，或一个 Int 类型
whatever it's expecting, whatever it's supposed to be.
或者任何它所期望的类型，任何应该传的类型
You don't even tell, you won't even know,
你甚至都不会发现
you won't even see NSNumber because the documentation
不会看到 NSNumber，因为有关的文档
is already being converted as well to show you.
是在转换后才展示给你看的
And similar, when things come out, if something comes
类似的，当数字出来的时候，如果某些东西
out of the API as an NSNumber,
作为 NSNumber 从 API 传出
you can work on it as a double or an int, or
你可以直接将它当做 Double 或者 Int 来使用
whatever is appropriate and it work just fine. But I just
或者其他任何合适的类型，它都会做得很好
mentioned in case you see it and wonder, what is that?
我在这里提一下它只是为了让你们在见到它的时候不感觉奇怪
Is this old Objective-C generic number holder?
它是久的 Objective-C 的泛型数字
It's easy to see create one from a double or
使用 Double 或者 Int 类型来新建一个 NSNumber
int by just using an initializer, right?
是很简单的，只需要使用初始化函数
NSNumbers sub 35.5, that's gonna give you
NSNumber(35.5)，它会给你
an NSNumber with the double 35.5 in it.
一个装着 35.5 的 NSNumber
And you can get the values out with vars on the number like
你也可以将这个变量所装的数字取出来
intValue, doubleValue, boolValue, they will give you.
通过就像 n.intValue n.boolValue，这样的方式
The return in a Swift type double, int, bool or
它们会返回 Swift 风格的 Double Int Bool 或其他
whatever. Okay, Date. Some of you already know about
对应的类型。好的，来讲 Date，你们有些人已经了解
Date because you did the extra credit maybe, in assignments 1
Date，因为你们可能已经做了作业 1 或者 2 中的
or 2. Date is just a way to represent any date and time.
额外加分的作业。Date 就是一种表示任意日期和时间的方式
You know internally it's represented, I think,
它内部可能表示的是...我认为是
like Number of seconds since 1970 or something like that.
像秒钟的数字，从 1970 年开始的，或者类似的表示方法
It's great for doing that, it's great for even small
这样做是很棒的，甚至对于一小段时间来说也是很棒的
amounts of time because the date includes the time down to
因为 Date 包含的时间精度小到
small you know, sub millisecond times.
比毫秒还小
But I just want you to note that with date there's
但关于 Date 值得注意的是
other classes that go along with it like Calendar,
另外有一些类和它的经常一起出现，比如说 Calendar
DateFormatter, DateComponents. DateComponents will give
DateFormatter, DateComponents, DateComponents 会给你
you things like the month and things like that. And
比如月份或者其他类似的
why are there all those other classes? Well because date,
为什么会有这些类呢？因为
if you're gonna put it in your UI, you have to be very
如果你想讲 Date 放进你的 UI 里，你必须要非常非常
careful. Around the world, dates are represented very,
小心，因为在全世界日期的表达方式是有
very differently, and it's not just that the name of a month
非常大的差异的。这差异不仅仅是在于在不同的语言中
is different in a different language.
月份等单词的拼写不同
It's that other locale, we call them around the world,
而是在世界上的其他地区
use completely different kinds of dating systems. Maybe even
会用完全不同的日期系统
a completely different calendar than we use. So
甚至是和我们的完全不同的历法
you really have to be careful if you're gonna put date in
因此当你要把日期放进你的 UI 的时候你一定要小心
your UI to understand all of these other classes.
你也一定要了解这些类
And there is plenty of documentation how to do it.
有不少官方文档告诉你如何做到这一点
But, and it is extra work. Now if you're just using date
但这是额外的工作。如果你只是在程序内部使用 Date
internally to like keep track of how
比如说用 Date 来记录
long your Concentration move, or set game move is taking,
移动你的 Concentration 或者设置游戏的步骤花了多少时间
obviously you don't need any of that other stuff. And
你显然不需要其他的那些类
finally there's data. Data is just a bag of bits,
最后我们有 Data, Data 只是一包位(0 与 1)
we use it to transfer data around a lot inside iOS API.
我们很多时候都是用它在 iOS API 中传送数据
For example if we got an image from the Internet,
比如说如果我们从网上下载了一张图片
from some URL, it would come in as a big bag of bits. And
从某个 URL 下载的，它就会像一包位(0 与 1)一样传进来
we have classes like UI image,
然后我们会有像 UIImage 的类
which I'm gonna talk about today.
我今天会讲到 UIImage
That can look into the bag a bit and
它们可以查看这一包位并
say, that's jpeg data and make an image out of it. Or
说，这个是 JPEG 类型数据并且以它来生成一张图片
look into a bag of bits, you know we have formatters that
或者查看这一包类，比如说我们有 Formatter 这个类
look and say that's json data. Good, who knows what JSON is,
它去看看并说，哦这是 JSON 数据。你们有谁知道 JSON 是什么
raise your hand if you've heard of JSON, okay,
如果你听说过 JSON 举起手来
great. So that's JSON data, we interpret it as JSON data. So
很棒，那么它就是 JSON 数据，我们就会把它理解为 JSON 数据
that's what this data struct is,
这就是这个 Data 的结构
it's just a bag of bits, and there's lots of methods to
它就是一包位，并且这儿有许多函数来将它
convert it to and from other kinds of things. That's it, so
转变成或转变自其他东西
that's all I wanted to mention is those quick things.
这就是我所有想要讲的
Now we can dive into our main topic today which is
让我们来开始我们今天的主题
a really cool one, which is Views. All right, so
这是很酷的主题，也就是视图
I don't want you to be confused about the word view.
好的，我不想让你们搞混这个单词视图(view)
I'm using it in two contexts. One is MVC.
我在两种语境下使用了它，一个是 MVC
One of the letters there is V for view. That means that
其中的字母 V 代表着视图(View)，它代表着
bunch of generic minions of your controller. That View,
你的控制器的那些泛型的仆从，这个 View
capital V View, contains a lot of views.
大写 V 的 View，装着许多的视图(view)
These views that I'm talking about, and what by these
我正在讲的这些视图(view)是指
Views, I mean a subclass of the iOS class UIView. So
iOS 中的 UIView 这个类的子类
that's what we're talking about today is these Views,
这就是我们今天要讲的主题，这些装在 MVC 中的视图(View)
these things in an MVC's view. Sorry for
中的视图(view)，很抱歉
the terminology being the same there but same word,
它们俩的术语是同一个单词
somewhat different meanings there. So what is a view?
但是它们是有不同的意思的。那么，视图是什么？
What is a sub class of UIView? It's essentially just
UIView 的子类是什么？ 它本质上就是在屏幕上的一个
a rectangle on screen that defines a coordinate,
矩形，这个矩形定义了坐标
a coordinate system. And
定义了一个坐标系
this is a coordinate system you're gonna use to draw, and
并且这个你会用这个坐标系来画图
it's also a coordinate system for
你也会用这个坐标系来
getting multi-touch events, right,
实现多点触控事件
with the fingers on the screen. It's hierarchical,
就是用手指划屏幕。它是有等级的
which means these rectangles live inside other rectangles,
也就是说这个矩形可能被装在另一个矩形内
live inside other rectangles, right?
另一个矩形也可能被装在第三个矩形内
So the views inside views inside views.
也就是在视图里的视图里的视图
And you saw this with Concentration.
你们在 Concentration 中已经见过它了
We had that top-level view which was black, and
我们有顶层的视图，也就是那个黑色区域
then inside that we had stack view.
而在它里面我们有层叠视图(UIStackView)
Remember that? So that was another view.
还记得吗？那就是另外一个视图了
Inside that stack view were three more stack views.
在那个层叠视图里面，我们还有三个层叠视图
Inside those three stack views were four card buttons. So
在那三个层叠视图里面，是四个卡片按钮
as the UI buttons, right. Plus you had other views like your
它们是 UIButton，你也有其他的视图
new game button, score, flip count, those are all views.
比如说你的“开始新游戏”按钮，分数，flip count 它们都是视图
And they are all kind of in each, you know,
它们都是被包含在另一个视图里面的
in a hierarchical representation.
就像在那个等级表示中
So the way that if you look at a particular view and
如果你要看指定的视图
you wanna see who its superview is,
并且想知道它的上级视图(superview)是什么
in other words the view it's in. You just ask the view for
也就是包含着它的那个视图，你只用访问那个变量的
the var superview. Okay. Now, it's an optional UIView
superview，它的类型是一个可选类型的 UIView
because it might not currently be on screen, right? So, it
因为这个视图目前可能没有出现在在屏幕上
might not be in a superview at this time. You could certainly
所以它现在可能还没有被装进一个上级视图，你当然可以把它
add it. And then the other way around if you have a view and
装进去。反过来，如果你有一个视图
you wanna say, what are all the subviews in it?
并且你想知道所有它的子视图(subview)都是什么
Like you wanna ask our blackview where,
就像你可能想知道我们那个全黑的视图
show me all your subviews like this top level stackview and
让它展示它所有的子视图，比如说最上层的层叠视图
the flip count, label and the score, and the new game
还有 flip count 这个标签，还有你的得分，还有那个"开始新游戏"
button. You get that with another view var called
按钮，你可以通过另一个叫做 subviews 视图变量来
subviews, which is, as you can see, an array of UIView. Okay,
得到它们，它是一个 UIView 的数组
so it's very simple to manage this. There is also a UI
那么做到这一点是非常简单的。还有一个 UIWindow 类
window which is like way up at the top, but we never pay any
它是在最顶层的，但在 iOS 中
attention to that in iOS. It's not like the Mac where you
我们不需要关注它。我们不会像在 Mac 中
have lots of windows on a big desktop. The UIWindow,
会在桌面上有许多窗口，对于那个 UIWindow
the only time you probably ever care about that maybe if
我们只需要在，比如说如果你想使
you had an app that like projected part of itself out
你的程序能将自己弹到
onto external screen or something. But forget that. So
一个外部窗口的时候才需要关系它。现在不用理会它
in this class we won't even mention UIWindow.
我们在这节课中甚至不会提到 UIwindow
It's probably subclass UIView anyway,
只需要知道它继承了 UIView
but we don't really talk about it. Now this hierarchy of
但我们不会讲到它。这个视图中装有视图的
views inside views, you build in Xcode in interface builder.
层级结构是需要你们在 Xcode 中的 interface builder 构建的，
Right, you saw how we built in Concentration,
你们已经在 Concentration 的例子中见过了
we drag things out, we clicked the embed stack view button,
我们将控件拖出来，点击 Embed in Stack 按钮
that kind of staff. So that's how we build this hierarchy,
类似这样的，这就我们构建这个层级结构的方法
put views inside views 99% of the time.
我们 99% 的时候都是将视图装在视图中的
But it can be done in code as well. And in your assignment
但这实际上也可以使用代码来完成。并且在你们的第三次作业中
3, I am gonna ask you to do both. Build view hierarchy in
我会让你们两种都做到，既要用 interface builder 来构建
an interface builder like you did in concentration. But
这个层级结构，就像你们在 Concentration 中做得一样
then also do some in code, as well. And
接着也要在代码中构建一些层级结构
the way you do that is by just saying addSubview to a view,
要用代码做到这一点只用写 addSubview() 到一个视图中
and it will add that view as one of the subviews.
这样它就会将那个参数中的视图加到当前视图的子视图中
The only tricky thing here is when you wanna pull it out for
而有些复杂的是，如果你想将一个视图取出来
If you wanna pull a view out of the view hierarchy,
如果你出于某种原因想将一个视图从
some reason.
这个结构层次取出
you send that message to the view itself.
你要像那个视图传递一个信息
Okay, you send it to the view, you want to remove and
你告诉它你想要移除
you say remove yourself from superview, with this remove
你告诉它你想将它从它的父视图移出
from superview. So it's a little different there.
用这个 removeFromSuperView() 函数，这里有一些不同
You send add to the enclosing view but you send
你对要装视图的视图传递 addSubview() 函数
remove to the actual view itself. Now where does this
而 removeFromSuperView() 是传递给要取出的那个视图的，那么这个
view hierarchy starts. What's the top containing view?
视图层次结构是从哪开始的？最顶层的视图是什么
Well of course that's like the black view in concentration,
那么在 Concentration 中那当然是那个黑色的视图
right, that very top view. And there is a very important var,
对吧，它是最顶层的视图，而在 UIViewController 中有一个
in UIView controller, called view.
非常重要的变量，叫做 view
And that view points to that black one at the top.
那个 view 是指向最顶层的那个黑色的视图的
And it's automatically wired up for
这是在 interface builder 中自动
you in interface builder, so you can always start there and
帮你建立好的连接，因此你总是可以从那里开始
kinda of work your way down through the hierarchy,
并且遍历你的视图层次结构
looking at the sub-views and going on down. So
看看它的子视图并接着往下找
var view which is a UIView, in UIViewController,
那么 view 这个变量，它是 UIView，存在 UIViewController中
very important var to know if you want to access your view
如果你想要直接访问你的视图层次结构，这是一个非常重要的
hierarchy directly. Now of course, you can also access
变量。那么你当然也可以
your view hierarchy at any point with an outlet. Right,
在任何地方使用出口（Outlet) 来访问你的视图层次结构
if you create an outlet like to a stack view,
如果你创建了一个 StackView 的 outlet
now you can look right at the stack view, and
那么你就可以直接访问这个 StackView
then start looking at its subviews if you want,
并且，如果你想的话，开始去找它的子视图
you don't have to start at the top and start looking down.
你不用从最顶层开始并往下找
You can use an outlet, just go to any view you want
你可以使用 outlet，用它在任意时间
at any time. All right, let's talk a little bit about
访问任何你想访问的视图。现在我们来讲讲
initializing a view, right? Getting initialized. Normally,
初始化视图，视图的初始化。一般来讲
as usual, we try to avoid doing init as much as we can,
我们会尽可能地避免使用 init()
with all those other ways we know. If you have to do a view
用我们知道的其他方法。但如果你一定要做视图的初始化
initializer cuz you just, a var that you just no way you
如果不做的话你就不知道该
can initialize it using all the other ways we know. Then
如何用其他我们知道的方法来初始化它
you have to understand that view has two initializers,
那么你必须要知道视图有两个初始化函数
init with frame and init with coder. Init with frame is
init(frame :CGRect) 和 init(coder :NSCoder)
the initializer you usd to create a view in code.
init(frame :CGRect) 是可以在代码中创建视图的方法
Init with coder is the initializer that's used when
init(coder :NSCoder) 是在你用
you build your view in an interface builder and
interface builder 创建视图后
it gets free stride and then your app runs. When it runs,
当你的程序开始运行的时候
it gets initialized with init with coder. The coder,
那个视图就被 init(coder :NSCoder) 初始化了
NSCoder is a protocol that handles this mechanism of
NSCoder 是一个协议可以让你在
freeze drying with interface builder and
interface builder 中先做定住的(freezed)视图
then re, resurrecting it when your app runs. So
并当你程序运行的时候初始化
you have to implement of both of these. And
因此这两个函数你都要实现
the reason you have to implement both
而你要实现这两个的原因
of these is cuz init with frame is a designated
是 init(frame :CGRect) 是一个指定的
initializer, okay. And so if you ever created a view from
初始化函数。只要你通过代码创建视图
code, you need, if you want your code to execute, it's
如果你想让你的代码执行
gonna have to do it. And then init with coder is a required
你必须要这么做。而 init(coder :NSCoder)
initializer because it's part of a protocol that UIView
是一个被需求的(required) 初始化函数，因为它是 UIView 所实现的
implements, this NSCoder protocol you see. Remember,
协议的一部分，就是 NSCoder 这个协议
if you implement a protocol and it has an init in it,
还记得如果你要实现一个协议，而那个协议中有初始化函数
it's required, okay. So you'd have to implement them both.
它是被需求的。所以你必须要将它们两个都实现
Now you can have some other function like set up or
而你可以有一些别的函数比如说 setup()
whatever and call that setup from them both. Although,
或其他什么的，然后从那两个初始化函数中调用 setup()
sometimes it's not that simple because if you're using
但有的时候不会这么简单，因为如果你要用
this mechanism to initialize your own vars, you're supposed
这个机制来初始化你自己的变量的话
to initialize your own vars before you call super.init.
你应该要先初始化你的变量再调用 super.init()
Okay, so you are gonna have to initialize those vars inside
所以你就要在这些初始化函数中初始化
these inits. Maybe you might have slightly duplicated
你自己的变量。也许在这里你会有一些
code there, doing that. But hopefully,
代码来做到这一点。最好的情况
you can avoid this init in UIView entirely. Okay, another
是你可以完全避开这些在 UIView 中的初始化函数
alternative to initializing the UIView is awakeFromNib().
另一个初始化 UIView 的方法是用 awakeFromNib()
Now awakeFromNib() is actually a function,
awakeFromNib() 实际上是一个函数
that is sent to every single object that comes out of
它被传给所有在 interface builder 文件中
an interbase face builder file.
的对象
Every UI button, every UIView controller,
所有的 UIButton，所有 UIViewController
everything that comes out of there, when it gets unfreezed,
所有在那个文件里的对象，当它们被解除限制(unfreezed)的时候
it gets sent awakeFromNib(). Now the only thing about
它们就被传递了 awakeFromNib() 那么有一点是
putting initialization there is, it will only work for
当在这里进行初始化的时候，它只对
views that come out of an interface builder file.
interface builder 中的视图有效
If you create a view with init when framed from code,
如果你用 init(frame :GCRect) 在代码中创建了一个视图
if you created one, this won't get called. Okay,
如果你这样创建了一个视图，这个函数是不会被调用的
this only happens when you get unfreeze write interface.
这个只有在 interface builder 中的对象被解除限制的时候才会被调用
NIB is kind of really old name for interface builder files,
NIB 是一个 interface builder files 的奇怪的简称
the IB and NIB meant interface builder. Okay, so
IB 和 NIB 代表着 interface builder
that's it for initialization of views. All right,
视图的初始化就讲完了
now let's talk about how we draw. We have this UIView.
那么现在我们来看看我们如何画图，我们有 UIView
Why do we want it? Well, we wanna draw.
我们为什么需要它呢？因为我们想画图
How do we draw? Before I can tell you how to draw,
我们如何画图？在我将如何画图之前
we've got to talk about some types,
我们要讲一些类型
four very important types. Okay, they all start with CG,
四个非常重要的类型，它们都以 CG 开头
like this one, CGFloat. CG stands for Core Graphics.
比如说这个 CGFloat，CG 是指 core graphics(核心图形)
Core Graphics is the underlying drawing system for
core graphics 是底层的画图系统
normal 2D drawing in iOS. There are other
用来在 iOS 中进行二维的画图
drawing systems for doing 3D and other things. Not gonna
还有其他的画图系统负责做三维画图和其他什么的
talk about those cuz we only have so much to talk about.
我不会讲它们，因为我们已经有很多要讲的了
We're just gonna talk about the base 2D drawing system,
我们只会讲在二维平面上画图
and it's called core graphics. So core graphics has these
而这叫做 core graphics, 而 core graphics
four types, they're just critical to be in the say
有四种类型，它们在画图中
anything about drawing, one is CGFloat. So all drawing is
有非常重要的作用。其中一个是 CGFloat，所有的画图
in an accordance system that's floating point numbers. So
都是在以浮点数为坐标的坐标系上完成的
you're drawing in a floating point coordinate system,
你是在浮点数的坐标系上进行画图的
not integers, they're floating points.
不是整数，是浮点数
When you say where you wanna draw, your every point you're
当你在表达你想在哪里画图的时候，你用的
just dealing with floating point numbers. And for
所有点的坐标都是浮点数类型的
those floating point numbers have to be CGFloat.
而那些浮点数必须要是 CGFloat
They cannot be doubles or regular float, they have to be
它们不能是 Double 或者普通的浮点类型
CGFloats. Luckily, there's an initializer for CGFloat.
它们必须是 CGFloat，幸运的是，CGFloat 中有构造函数
We'll let you create a CGFloat from a double, but
它可以让你以 Double 类型创建一个 CGFloat 类型
CGFloat is the fundamental, kind of coordinate value,
但 CGFloat 是最基础的，像坐标值一样的
a floating point co-ordinate value. All drawing, all your
一个浮点类型的坐标值。所有的画图
code that's drawing is gonna have CGFloats. Now, of course,
所有关于画图的代码必须要用 CGFloat
there is CGPoint, which is just a struct with two things
当然我们也有 CGPoint，它是一个结构体
in it, x and y, which are both CGFloats. And there's CGSize,
包含两个对象，x 和 y，它们都是 CGFloat。我们还有 CGSize
which is a struct that has two things in it, two CGFloats,
它是一个一个结构体包含两个 CGFloat
width and height. Okay, so you got float, CGFloat the base
width(宽) 和 height(高)，那么现在你有 CGFloat
thing, then you got point and size. And of course,
它是最基本的，你有 点(CGPoint) 和 大小(CGSize)
you can combine point and size into very important CGRect.
当然你可以将点和大小合并到一个非常重要的类型： CGRect
Now CGRect is just finds a rectangle obviously,
CGRect 显然是一个矩形
including your views entire bounds, that rectangle or
它可以是你整个视图的边界的那个矩形
any rectangle you wanna draw inside your coordinate system
或者其它任何你想在你的坐标系中画的矩形
you're gonna use this. And it has a number of initializers
你都要用到它。它有不少的初始化函数
including initializing by origin and size.
包括以 origin(原点) 和 size(大小) 来初始化
Also intializer that takes xy width, height, etc.
或者是以 x y 坐标和宽与高来初始化之类的
And it also has a whole slew of other vars and
它也有非常多的其他的变量
functions for manipulating rects, like vars like minX,
和函数，用来控制一个矩形，比如说叫做 minX 的变量
which gives you the minimum x value of your rectangle.
它会给你在这个矩形中最小的 x 的坐标值
Or, intersects that takes another rect and
或者 intersects 函数，它接收另一个矩形做参数
returns a bool whether the two rectangles intersect.
并返回一个布尔值，表示这两个矩形是否相交
There's also intersect which returns a new rect
还有 intersect 函数，它会返回一个新的矩形
which is the intersection of two overlapping rectangles.
这个矩形是两个矩形的相交部分
It also has contains CGPoint, which will tell you whether
它也有 contains(CGPoint) 它会告诉你
there's a point, that is point is inside CGRect. So
这个矩形中是否有某个点
there's tons, this probably two or three dozens methods so
它有许多这样的东西，这大概有 12 - 36 这样的函数
definitely check out the documentation CGRect,
你们一定要看看 CGRect 的文档
because it'll make your code a lot cleaner. And actually,
这样会让你们的代码更加地简洁
you're gonna see in the demo that I do on Wednesday.
那么你们也可以在我周三要做的示例中看到
I actually even extend CGRect to add five or six more
我要扩展 CGRect 来加上 5、6 个新的
a little convenience functions because CGRect turned out
便于使用的小函数，因为 CGRect 是你代码中
to be so important in all the code that you write.
非常重要的一个类型
When you're doing drawing. So now you know those four types,
当你在画图时。现在你们认识了这四个类型
let's talk about the coordinate system we're gonna
让我们来讲讲我们要在其中画图的
be drawing in here. The most important thing to know
坐标系。
besides the fact that it's floating point precision to
除了我们的点的精度是浮点型
draw is that the origin is in the upper left, not lower
另一件很重要的事是我们坐标的原点是在左上角的
Left. The lower left would be Cartesian coordinates,
而不是左下角，原点在左下角的坐标系是笛卡尔坐标系
you know, like you have in Math class. Lower left alk,
就像你们数学课中的坐标系一样，Mac 上的
also happens to be the coordinate system on the Mac,
坐标系的原点也是在左下角的
okay. But in iOS, it's in the upper left,
但在 iOS 中，原点是在左上角的
and that means that increasing values of y go down towards
这就意味着当你增加 y 的值的时候
the bottom of the screen. So for example, I got this point
你的点是在像屏幕的下方移动的。比如说
over here on the side there. See it up there, 500, 35.
我在这里有一个点，看到这，它的坐标是 500，35
It's 500 over and 35 down, right, way over and way down.
它是在原点右边 500 个单位长度，原点下方 35 个单位长度，一个坐标表示右方，一个表示下方
So that's x of 500, and it actually really would be 500.0
因此它的 x 值是 500，呃它实际上是 500.0
and 35.0 cuz they're floating point values, right? Okay,
和 35.0，因为它们是浮点数，对吧
the unit in this coordinate system are called points.
这个坐标系中的单元叫做点(point)
Points are not the same as pixels.
点和像素 (pixel) 是不同的
Pixels are the little dots that the screen is made of.
像素是组成屏幕的小点
Some screens have a lot of little pixels, very,
一些屏幕有许多的小像素
very high resolution, what we call Retina Displays.
有着非常非常高的分辨率，我们叫它们 Retina 显示屏
You've probably heard that phrase. Lots of pixels per
你们应该听说过这个短语。许多像素
point. Why is that good? Well, because remember you can draw
组成一个点，为什么这样很棒？ 因为还记得你们可以在
on floating point boundaries, so you can draw at 27.3, 27.6,
浮点值的点的边界上画图，那么你就可以在 27.3 27.6
28, right? You could be drawing in between points. And
28 这些点画点，你也可以在点之间画图
you get these very smooth curves or
这样你就能在 Retina 显示屏上得到一条非常光滑的曲线
whatever on a Retina Display. On a lower res display,
或者其他什么。而在低分辨率的时候
maybe there's only one pixel per every point, and so
可能是一个像素对应着一个点
it's kind of more jaggy when you draw. But you don't draw
这样的话你画的图就不会那么平整光滑，但这里我们画的边界
on pixel boundaries, you draw on point boundaries.
不是像素，而是由点构成的边界
That way, even if you had a lot of pixels per point,
这样的话，景观你可能在一个点中有许多像素
it looks the same size basically as on a lower
它们在更低分辨率的屏幕上看起来也差不多
resolution device. Okay, it's not as smooth as on a high
是一样大小的，不会像在高分辨率的屏幕上那么
resolution device but it's the same size cuz it's zoom point.
平滑，但它的大小会是相同的，因为它是放大的点
You can find out how many pixels per point your device
你可以用 UIView 中的 contentScaleFactor
has by using UIView content scale.factor who turns
来确定你的屏幕上一个点是由多少个像素构成的
a float, it's currently gonna either be one, two, or
它的返回类型是 CGFloat，这个值可能会是 1、2 或者 3
three. And it's gonna tell you how many pixels are are there
它表示这一个点是由多少个像素构成的
per point. All right,
好了
the most important rectangle in all of UIView is bounds,
在所有 UIView 中最重要的矩形是 bounds
it's var on UIView to CGRect. It tells you the bounds,
它是一个在 UIView 中的 CGRect，它告诉你
the coordinates of your drawing system, the origin and
你画图的坐标系的边界是什么，它告诉你画图区域的原点
the width and height in your own drawing coordinate system.
画图区域的宽和高是什么
And one thing you have to understand is,
你们必须要理解的一点是
different views have different coordinate systems.
不同的视图是有不同的坐标系的
Okay, they each have their own coordinate system,
它们都有各自的坐标系
this bounds is in yours. So when you're drawing,
而这个 bounds 是在你的坐标系中的，所以当你画图的时候
you always use bounds. Now there are a couple of other
你一定要用 bounds。还有其他一些东西
things like frame. Var frame, sounds a lot like bounds.
像 frame，frame 这个变量，听起来很像 bounds
Frame has nothing to do with your drawing. Nothing,
frame 和你的画图一点关系都没有
it's a Rect, but has nothing to do with your drawing.
它是一个矩形，但和你画图一点关系都没有
The frame is where you are in your superview.
frame 表示的是这个视图在它的父视图的位置
So frame this not even in your coordinates system,
因此 frame 甚至不在你的坐标系中
in it's your superview's coordinate system.
它是在这个视图的父视图的坐标系中的
Says, where you are? Similar with center.
它表示你在哪里， center 也是类似的
Center is not the center of your drawing area, it's
center 并不是代表你画图区域的中心
the center of view in your superview. So frame in center
它表示的是你的父视图的中心，因此 frame 和 center
are, where you are? Bounds is the place you're drawing.
表示的是你在哪里，bounds 表示的是你画图的区域
Don't get these things confused. I have a slide down
别把这些东西弄混了，这里有一页简单讲解
here, go through it quick, we never use frame or
的幻灯片。我们不会用 frame
center to draw because it has nothing to do with drawing,
或 center 来画图，因为它们和画图没有任何关系
it has to do with positioning.
它们和处理视图的位置有关系
And you might think that the frame and the bounds
你可能会认为 frame 和 bounds 所表示的区域
are gonna be the same size, but views can be rotated. And
会用同样的面积，但视图是可以被旋转的
if you imagine rotating your view, the bounds get rotated
而想象当你旋转你的视图的时候，bounds 会被跟着
with, okay, so they stay the same size, but the frame now
以前转，所以它的面积会保持不变
has to get bigger. To totally enclose this because it's
但现在 frame 要变得更大，才能完全将这个视图装进去
a diamond shaped, right, View B is a diamond shape. Okay, so
因为这个视图现在是菱形了，B 视图是一个菱形
the frames' sized-out width and height are not the same
因此 frame 的大小与宽和高并不
necessarily as the bounds' sized width and height.
一定是和 bounds 的宽和高是相等的
Don't ever think of them as the same.
别去想它们是一样的
If you ever use your frame to draw in this class,
在这节课中如果你用 frame 去画图
you'll get dinged, that is just wrong.
你会被扣分，因为那是错的
All right, so now we know the bounds of where we
好的，现在我们知道了用来在其中画图的 bounds
are drawing. We know we have this coordinate system in
我们知道我们有这个坐标系
the upper left. How do we create one of these views?
它以左上角为原点，那么我们如何创建这些视图呢
Okay, we wanna create one. Well,
我们想要创建一个视图
I told you that you mostly do it in Interface Builder, but
我告诉过你们我们多数会在 Interface Builder 中做
if I have a custom view. Let's say I have a custom view,
但如果我有一个自定义的视图，比如说我有一个自定的视图用来
draw something special to just me.
画一些只对我来说有意义的东西
How do I drag that out into Interface Builder? Right,
我该怎么将它从 Interface Builder 的控件中拉出来？
Interface Builder's got that nice list in the lower right
Interface Builder 在右下角有
corner of UIButton, UILabel, all those cool things.
一个可用的控件的列表，比如说 UIButton，UILabel 还有其它的
My view's not gonna be there, right?
我的视图不在那其中，对吧
So how do I make one? Well, it turns out you drag out
那么我如何做一个呢？其实你可以将一个
a generic one. Currently, as of this my speaking,
普通的视图拉出来，在我这里看就是
it's the second from the bottom in that long list.
那个长长的列表中的倒数第二个
It's called UIView down there. You drag a generic one out and
它叫做 UIVIew，你将一个普通的视图拉出来
then you're going to inspect it, but you're gonna use
接着你要去检查(inspect)它，但你要用到一个
a little different inspector in the upper right than you
有些不同的检查器(inspector)，它在右上角
usually do. It's not the Attributes Inspector,
它不是 Attributes Inspector（属性检查器）
it's the Identity Inspector. I think it's the tab,
而是 Identity Inspector(身份检查器)，它应该就是在
just one to the left of the Attributes Inspector. And
Attributes Inspector 左边的标签页
in there, the top thing is going
在哪里，最上面的
to be the class of the thing you're inspecting and
会是你要检查的那个类
it's gonna be UIView when you first drag it out. And you're
当你视图拖出来的时候，它应该是 UIView，而你要做的
just going to change the pull down there to pick your class.
就是将它改成那个下拉界面中你的类
So now you have a view there, but it's of your class.
那么你在这里就有一个视图了，而它是由你类创建的
That's how you're gonna create one of your custom views. Now,
这就是你创建一个自己的自定义视图的方法
the other way you can create views is in code.
另一种创建视图的方法是用代码
And again, I'm gonna ask you to do this both ways in your
还有，我会要求你们在你们的第三次作业中
assignment three. And you do that just by calling the frame
将这两种方法都用到。而你只需要调用 UIView(frame: myFrame)
UIView with frame initializer that we talked about before.
这个我们讲过的以 frame 初始化视图的初始化函数
You can also set UIView open parenthesis, close
你也可以调用 UIView()
parenthesis, then your frame will be 0000, upper left,
那么你的 frame 就会是 0 0 0 0，在
no size. And you can then just set that frame var,
左上角，没有大小。而你接着就可以将这个
that I talked about a couple slides ago, to position and
我在前几张幻灯片中讲过的 frame 变量设置到合适的位置
size, this view in the super view. Okay,
并设置合适的大小，来确定这个视图在它父视图中的位置
just always remember the frame, though,
一定要记得 frame
is in the super view's coordinate system,
是在父视图的坐标系中的
it's saying where you are.
它表示的是你在哪
Nothing to do with your drawing,
与你画图无关
just where you are. Okay, so here's an example.
只是表示你在哪。好的，这里有一个例子
I'm gonna create a UILabel in code. Okay, UILabel, you
我会在代码中床架一个 UILabel，你们知道
know what that is, right? It shows text, that's the thing
UILabel 是什么，对吧。它能展示文字
that said flipped colon 0, that was a UILabel. Of course,
我们做的 flipped : 0 就是一个 UILabel
UILabel inherits from UIView.
当然，UILabel 继承自 UIView
It's a rectangular area on screen. All rectangular areas
它是屏幕上的一个矩形区域，屏幕上的所有矩形区域
on screen are UIViews. So, I'm gonna create a rectangle to
都是 UIView，因此我会创建一个矩形
say where it's gonna be. This rectangle is gonna be in
它表示着我的视图会在哪里。这个矩形会在
the super view's coordinate system. In this case,
父视图的坐标系里，在这个例子中
I'm gonna put the label at the very top level.
我会将我的 UILabel 放在最顶层
In other words, the black view of Concentration, I'm putting
也就是我们 Concentration 中的那个黑色的视图
it right over that level. So this 20 across and 20 down and
我会将它放在那个视图中，那么这个 x:20, y:20
a width of 100 and height of 50, that's in the black views,
widt:100, height:50 这个矩形是在黑色的视图中的
the top level views coordinate system. And then I created
在最顶层的视图的坐标系中。接着我用 frame
a UILabel using that frame. I set the label's text to hello.
创建了一个 UILabel，我将 label 中的文字设置为 hello
Nothing's happening on screen right there, yeah.
到这里在屏幕上还没有任何事情发生
Now, I need to add it as a subview of that black view, so
现在我需要将它以子视图的形式加入到黑色的视图中
I'm gonna assume this code is in a view controller and
那么假设这段代码是在一个 view controller 中的
I'm gonna use that very special var view.
那么我就会使用那个特殊的变量 view
And say, view, add subview this label. Now that
接着我只用写 view.addSubview(label)
UI label gets added as a subview of the top level view,
那么这个 UILabel 就被当做子视图加入到 Concentration 中最顶层的
the black view in concentration,
那个黑色的视图中了
it's white here, and it gets put at 20, 20,
在这里是白色的视图。它被放置在了最顶层的坐标系中
100 50 in that top level views coordinate system. Remember,
的 (20,20) (100,50) 这个位置
upper left is 00. So, that means down from the upper left
记得，左上角是(0,0)，这意味着它是在左上角的下方的
corner. Everybody got that? So that's how you add view,
所有人都懂了吗？这就是你如何添加视图的方法
it's very easy just add subview. That's how you put
添加子视图是非常简单，这就是你将
view on screen from code. All right, so when would I wanna
代码中的视图放到屏幕上的方法。好的，我应该什么时候
create my own UIView subclass versus just using UIButton or
创建自己的 UIView 子类而什么时候直接用 UIButton
UILabel? Those are UIView subclasses.
或 UILabel？它们也是 UIView 的子类
Well, if I obviously want to do custom drawing or
如果我想要自定义地画图
if I want to handle some custom touch events,
或者想要处理一些自定义的点击事件(touch event)
pinches or something like that.
缩放或者其他的
I'll talk about handling touch events on Wednesday, but
我会在周三讲处理点击事件
today we're gonna focus on drawing. So we're going to do
今天我们重点在画图，我们今天完全都是画图
all drawing today. So to draw, it could not be easier,
要画图是再简单不过的了
there's only one way to draw, okay, in all of iOS. Which
在所有的 iOS 中，只有一种画图的方式
is you override this function in UIView and implement it.
就是重写(override)并实现 UIView 中的这个函数(draw)
That is the only way to draw. You can't call any functions
这是画图的唯一方式，你不能在这个函数外调用任何
that draw or anything outside of this method,
画某些东西的函数
it's the only way to draw. So that makes really simple,
它是画图的唯一方法，这就十分简单
you don't have to worry about any other mechanism cuz this
你不用考虑其他任何的机制
is the only one there is. And so inside this draw method,
因为这就是唯一的方法，而在这个 draw 函数中
you're going to draw in your bounds,
你要在你的 bounds 中画图
whatever custom drawing you do. Okay,
不论你要画什么
never call this method ever. This method,
永远不要调用这个函数
you override and implement your drawing,
你重写并实现的这个画图的函数
you never call it. If you want your view to be redrawn,
你绝对不要去调用它，如果你因为某些事件发生
because something about you has changed, you call one of
而想要重画你的视图，你要
these two methods on yourself, setNeedsDisplay or
自己调用这两个函数之一，setNeedsDisplay()
setNeedsDisplay with rect. Okay, and
或者 setNeedsDisplay(_ rect: CGRect)
that tells the system, hey, my view needs to be redrawn,
这告诉操作系统，我的视图需要被重画
please, redraw it. So, only the system, only iOS
请重画它。只有系统，只有 iOS
calls your draw and you can make it call it, or tell it
才可以调用你的 draw 函数，而你可以让系统去调用它
you want it to call it anyway, by calling setNeedsDisplay.
或者告诉系统你逍遥调用它，通过调用 setNeedsDisplay
Now notice this rect, see the draw rect. What is that
注意到这个 rect，看这个 draw(rect)
rect argument, both up on draw and down in set needs display.
这个 rect 参数，既在 draw 中也在 setNeedsDisplay 中出现
That is purely an optimization rectangle, okay. That's if,
它只是一个用来优化的矩形
for example, you had another view on top of view and
举个例子，比如说你在当前上还有一个视图
it went away and it exposed a little rectangle of view,
当上面的那个遮住当前的视图离开后，它会暴露出当前视图的一个矩形区域
the system would call your draw with just that rectangle.
那么系统就以那个矩形区域来调用 draw
But you are allowed to redraw your whole view if you want.
但你也可以去重画整个视图
But if you can be efficient about only drawing
但如果只重画暴露出来的
the rectangle that was exposed,
那个矩形部分
then you can be efficient. So it's purely an optimization.
是更加有效率的。所以它只是一个优化
You can ignore it if you want, just draw your whole view.
如果你想的话可以完全无视它，直接重画整个视图
So if you have a simple view that's easy to draw,
如果你有一个画起来很简单的视图
doesn't use a lot of resources and not 3D graphics or
画它不会占用非常多的资源，不需要 3D 图形
something, then you can just ignore that rect. All right,
或其他那些，那你就可以完全无视它
so how do I implement this draw rect? Okay, I overwrite
那么我该如何实现这个 draw 函数
it now I want to draw. So how are we gonna do it?
我重写了它，而我现在想要画图，我们该怎么做呢
We're gonna do it using core graphics,
我们要用到 core graphics
this underlie drawing level layer. And the basic way
它是画图系统的底层。而一般的做法
to do it is, you get what's called a drawing context and
是你要先得到画图的环境(drawing context)
you ask that context to draw lines and
接着你要求它去话线条
stuff, okay. Now, there's also an objects orientated way to
和其他什么。还有一种面向对象的
draw with a class called UIBezierPath.
画图方式是用叫做 UIBezierPath 的类
UIBezierPath, same concept.
UIBezierPath 是一样的道理
It's just putting a little bit of an object or in the way you
它就是让你的画图有面向对象的元素
can build an object that contains some drawing.
你可以创建一个包含着一些画图内容的对象
Which is nice if you wanna repeatedly draw that object,
这样当你想用重复地画那个对象是非常方便的
maybe with different colors, whatever. So let's talk about
你可能想要用不同的颜色或者之类的。我们来讲讲
the fundamental core concept of drawing in core graphics,
core graphics 中画图的核心的基本概念
how do we do it?
我们该怎么做
The number one thing about core graphics is that it's
第一件事是 core graphics 是基于
context based, so you have to get a context. UIBezierPath
环境的，所以你必须要有一个环境
will automatically get the context for
UIBezierPath 会自动帮你获得环境
you, but if you don't use UIBezierPath,
但如果你不用 UIBezierPath
you have to get a context. Now, in draw(Rect),
你必须要获得一个环境。那么在 draw(Rect) 函数中
you can you use this Swift global function,
你可以使用这个 Swift 中的全局函数
UIGraphicsGetCurrentContext and it will give you a context
UIGraphicsBeginImageContext 而它会给你可以用来
to draw, okay. But there could be other contexts, printing or
画图的环境，但还有其他得到画图环境的方法
drawing on and off screen buffer,
打印或者在屏幕缓存中画图之类的
I'm not gonna talk about those, but there are other
我不会讲到那些，但确实
ways to get context as well. But when you're in draw(Rect),
是有其他的得到环境的方法的。但当你在 draw(Rect) 函数中
it's easy. You just call this one global function,
你只需要简单地调用这个全局函数就可以了
it will give you the context you are currently drawing in.
它会给你你正在画图的环境
Okay, once you have the context,
好的，当你得到环境后
now you use the context to create what are called paths.
你要用它来创建路径(path)
Paths are just arcs and line to's and
路径就是弧和线段
then move to's, which is like jump over a little bit.
还有 move to，move to 就像是中间空了一段的
It's just a combination of all those, that is what a path is.
路径就是那些东西的组合
So you're gonna build some path.
那么你需要创建一些路径
Then, you're gonna set a bunch of drawing attributes,
接着你要设置一些画图的属性
like the color you want to draw in, any fonts, kind of.
比如说你想要用什么颜色，什么字体之类的
That's a drawing attribute, we'll talk about fonts in
这些是画图的属性，我们一会儿会讲到
a bit, but line widths, textures, things like that.
字体，还有线段宽度，纹理(texture)
You set all those things up and then you do one of
你将那些属性设置好，接着你对你的路径
two things with your path, you stroke it or you fill it. So,
做这两件事之一：你将它 stroke(描边)，或者将它 fill(填充)
stroke it means draw a line along my path, you know,
将它 stroke 意味着沿着我的路径画一条线
with a certain line width and color, and fill means fill in
用一定的线宽度和颜色，而将它 fill 意味着
the area that my line encloses. Believe it or not,
将这个路径所包围的区域填充。无论你信不信
this is the only way to draw, basically, in.
这是在 core graphics 中
Core graphics and you might like, wow, that seems really
画图的唯一方式，你可能会觉得
limiting. All I can do is arcs and lines and fill them in and
这是很受限的。我能做的只是画弧和线段并 fill 或者
stroke them, but it's amazing what you can do when you build
stroke 它们，但当你在这个原始的强力的
on top of that primitive powerful mechanisms, okay, and
画图机制之上画图时，会是非常棒的
we will talk about that. So UIBezierPath does the same
我们会讲到它的。那么 UIBezierPath
thing, it just does a lot of it under the covers but it has
也是做的同样的事，但它是在后台完成的大部分工作
methods for setting line with, and things like that.
它有用来设置线宽度之类的属性东西的函数
It has method to stroke and a method to fill, and
它有用来 stroke 和 fill 的函数
a methods to do arc to and line to and all that thing. So
也用用来画弧和线段之类的函数
it's just a kind of arbitrated collecting bag of that. So
UIBezierPath 就像是一个用来画图的面向对象的集合
let's look what the code looks like.
让我们来看看代码应该是怎样的
To draw a triangle using this mechanism.
如果我们要用这个机制来画一个三角形
So first time,I will do with UIBezierPath. I'm gonna create
第一次我将会用 UIBezierPath 来做
UIBezierPath, it has a lot of initialization but
我要创建一个 UIBezierPath，它有许多初始化函数
I'm gonna use the one that just create an empty path.
我要用那个创建一个空路径的初始化函数
That create a new, there is nothing in it.
这回创建一个新的 UIBezierPath，它里面什么都没有
Now I am gonna move around, I am gonna start by moving to
接着我要移动我的点，我以移动到
a point you see that 80 across and 50 down.
(80,50) 为开始
Let us assume that this screen is 160 points across and
我们假设我们的屏幕宽度是 160 点
you know 300 or 400 high. So I am moving halfway across and
300 或 400 点高。所以我是从左上角向右
50 points down from the top my margin is up on the left.
移动了一半的屏幕宽度，向下移动了 50 个点
Now am gonna add a line down to 140 over,
那么我要添加一条连到 (140,150) 的线段
almost to the edge of the screen up there, and
它快到屏幕的边缘了
150 down then I'm gonna add another line. You see how
接着我要添加另外一条线，你看我
I'm just calling functions on my UIBezierPath to add lines,
正在以我的 UIBezierPath 调用函数来添加线段
right? So there is another one over here. Then I'm gonna
我在这里也还有一个这样的调用。接着我要
close my path so there is a method in UIBezierPath called
封闭我的路径。而在 UIBezierPath 中有一个
close which draws a line back to where you started,
叫做 close() 的函数会画一条到你开始的点的线
wherever that was. So, I'm gonna close my path.
不论你是从哪开始的，这样就能闭合我的路径
And there's a lot of tons of methods in UIbezierPath you
在 UIBezierPath 中有许多函数
have to go look at the documentation. But here's
你需要在官方文档中查阅它们
a simple, those are simple method usage, right? Now I
但这个函数用起来还是挺简单的对吧
kind of been tricking you because you'd look at this and
我可能有点让你们误解了，因为你们看到我写了这些
it looks like as I called these, it draws on screen, but
当我调用这些函数的时候，屏幕上就会出现图形了
no. I just wanted to kind of give you visualization what's
但实际上并不是这样的。我这里这样做只是想给你们视觉上的
going on. In fact, when I did all that, nothing happened on
感知，告诉你们发生了什么，但实际上
screen. There was absolutely nothing happening,
当我调用完这些函数，屏幕上是什么都没有的
all I was doing was building this UIBezierPath object up.
我所做的只是将这个 UIBezierPath 对象创建好
If I wanna appear on scree I have to set my drawing
如果我想让它画在屏幕上，我要设置我的画图的
attributes and tell it to stroke or fill. So
属性，并且告诉它是要去 stroke 还是 fill
let's do that. Now we set our colors both our fill color and
那么让我们开始吧，我们用 UIColor 这个类来设置我们的
stroking color using UIColor class. So
fill 的颜色和 stroke 的颜色
we don't set it on our UIBezierPath,
我们不是在 UIBezierPath 对象上设置它的
we actually use color and
我们是用 UIcolor 来设置它们的
we say things like UIColor.green.setFill().
我们写 UIColor.green.setFill()
Well, green is a static var on UIColor,
green 是 UIColor 的静态数据成员
meaning it's a class like a class color,
意味着它是表示类所代表的颜色
just like get unique identifier was in card. And
就像我们之前的在 card 中的 getUniqueIdentifier
it just gets the green color and it has about 10 or
它会给我们绿色，而这个类有差不多
12 predefined colors, red, green, blue, magenta, cyan,
10 个还是 12 个预设好的颜色，红色，绿色，蓝色，洋红色，青色
that kind of stuff. We could also make colors.
那些的。我们也可以制作颜色
We could use a color literal there.
我们在那里也可以用 color literal
Remember when we did the color literal? Perfectly legal to
还记得我们之前用 color literal 的代码吗，写
say colorLiteral.setFill. So we're setting our fill color
colorliteral.setFill() 是完全合法的，那么现在我们设置了
and our stroke color. So we're gonna fill with green.
fill 和 stroke 的颜色，我们 fill 的颜色是绿色
Our triangle is gonna be filled with green and
我们的三角形会被绿色填充
the line is gonna be drawn With red and
而它的线条则会用红色来画
I'm also going back to the BezierPath and saying,
我还会回到我的 UIBezierPath 对象
set the line with to three points wide on a high
并将线段宽度设置为 3.0，在高分辨率的显示器上
resolutions play that will be nine pixels wide. So
它会是 9 个像素宽
it's a fairly thick line, not that thick that but, so
那么这是一条相对比较粗的线条，不会特别粗
now that I have set these things up now I can stroke and
那么现在我把这些属性设置好了，我就可以 stroke 和
fill. So let us first fill And
fill 了，让我们先开始 fill
when I fill I get this notice there's no line around
当我 fill 的时候，我得到了这个东西，注意到
the edge I just get the fill of my path that I made.
在它的边缘是没有线的，因为我只是 fill 了我的创建的路径
And then when I stroke now I get the red 3 point wide line
接着当我 stroke 时候，我就得到了这三条 3.0 宽的线
around. Yeah? >> Where this is
>>这段代码是在哪里写的？
written? >> Where this is written?
Like where you put this? In your draw rect.
你是想问我们要将这些代码放在哪吗，放在你的 draw(rect)
In that draw method, that we override in UIView,
在那个我们重写的那个 draw() 函数里
that's where this code goes. >> So, when I drag a UIView
就是放这段代码的地方。>>[学生提问]
out to the storyboard, do I have to make an outlet to,
>>[学生提问]
like, have- >> Okay, so the question is,
>>那么他的问题是
when I drag a UIView out into my storyboard and
当我将一个 UIView 拖进我的 storyboard 中
I set it to my custom class,
并且将它设置为我自己写的类
do I have to like do an outlet or something? No, you just,
我要写一个 outlet 还是什么吗？不用的
in your custom code, implement your draw with that kind of
你只用在你自己写的类中实现那个带有那个优化的矩形
optimization rect argument and put this code in there, and
的参数的 draw 函数，并且将这段代码放在那里面
every time the system has your view on screen it
接着每当系统将你的视图放上屏幕的时候
will draw this. Now it's very efficient it's only gonna ask
它就会画这个。现在的设计非常有效率，除非某些变量改变了
you to draw once unless things change, but it's gonna draw it
系统只会画一次，但系统的确是会帮你画的
for you. So all the whole, all the drawing is on demand,
所以说所有的画图过程都是按需的
right? The system asks you to draw, it calls your function,
系统教你去画图，它会调用你的函数
you implement this code and
你实现这段代码
it draws on demand. You never force draw.
那么它就会按照系统的需求来画图，你从不会强迫它画图
The only way you can kind of force drawing,
你唯一可以让它强制画图的方法就是调用
is that setNeedsDisplay. And even that's just telling
setNeedsDisplay()，但这样也只是告诉系统
the system to please draw me as soon as possible, but not
如果可行的话，请将我画出来
instantly. It's all on demand drawing. So, this is how
但不是立即画出来。画图都是按需画图的
you would implement. This code would be in your draw rect.
这就是你实现的方法，这些代码都会在你的 draw(rect) 中
We call it dra_rect, it used to be called draw rect.
我们以前叫它 draw(rect)
Now it's called draw under bar rect, but I suppose we
而现在它叫做 draw(_ rect)
can call it the draw method, but we call it dra_rect,
我想我们可以叫它 draw 函数，但我叫它 draw(rect)
it's got that rect argument, okay, that optimization.
因为它有那个用来优化的 rect 参数
All right, now you can use UIBezierPath also to create
你可以用 UIBezierPath 来创建一些
some very common paths like a rounded rectangle which we'll
普通的路径，比如说圆角的矩形
use in our demo cuz we're gonna do a playing card, which
在我们的示例中我们会创建一个牌，因此我们会用到圆角矩形
has a rounded rectangle. You can also do circles, ovals,
你也可以用 UIBezierPath 的其他的
things like that using other initializers of UIBenzierPath.
初始化函数来创建类似圆形，椭圆形之类的
#TODO: clip your drawing??
Note that you can use your BezierPath to clip
注意你们可以用 UIBezierPath 来修剪
your drawing. You'll definitely want this for
你的画图，你们肯定会在作业中用到这个
your homework, pay attention here. So
打起精神来
what that means is you draw some shape like your triangle.
那么这就意味着当你话一些类似三角形的形状
And if you send add clip to your path,
接着你对你的路径对象调用 addClip() 函数
now all future drawing will be inside that triangle. Even if
那么之后所有的画图都会画在那个三角形中
you draw outside, anything outside gets clipped off.
甚至当你画到外面的时候，所有画到外面的部分都会被剪掉
So that can be really convenient for your homework.
那么这对你们的作业来说是会有很大的好处的
That's my hint for you. You can also do hit detection
这是给你们的一点提示，你们也可以做包含检测
like is this point in the triangle, right?
比如说这个三角形是否包含这个点
Using this contains point method and
用到这个 contains(point) 函数
a lots of other stuff. So check the documentation for
还有其他的很多东西，记得去查阅
UIBezierPath of the things that you can do.
UIBezierPath 的文档，去了解你能做些什么
All right, let's go and talk about UIColor, right? Okay,
好的，让我们来讲讲 UIColor
first setting the fill and stroke something like that.
我们先后设置了 fill 和 stroke 的颜色
We know a lot of ways to create colors. Color literals,
我们已经知道很多创建颜色的方法，有 color literal
also the static function I mentioned. You can also create
还有我讲过的那个静态函数，你也可以用
them with initializer to take RGB values.
接受 RGB 值的初始化函数来创建颜色
Or HSB which is hue saturation and brightness or
或者接受 HSB 值的初始化函数，也就是色相，饱和度，亮度
even a pattern. You can create a color that's actually
或者甚至一个接受图案的初始化函数，你可以用一个图案来
a pattern some image, just like repeated, right,
创建一个颜色，就像循环一样
which is kinda cool. And we also know that views have
这挺酷的。我们知道我们的视图是可以有背景颜色的
the background color, right? We set the background color
我们给我们的 Concentration 中的那个
of our base view in Concentration be black.
基视图设置为黑色
We set the background color of our buttons to be orange, so
我们将我们的按钮的背景颜色设置为橙色
there's a var for that of course, in view. Colors also,
那么在视图中当然是有表示背景颜色的变量的
importantly, can be transparent. A transparent
非常重要的一点，颜色可以是透明的，你是可以
color you can kind of see through it a little bit and
看到透明的颜色的后面的东西的
we specify transparency using something called alpha.
我们用一个叫做 alpha 的东西来设置透明度
How many people have heard the term alpha drawing? Okay, so
你们有多少人听过 alpha drawing 这个术语
most of you know this, great. So, we use alpha. Alpha of 0
哦大部分人都知道，很好。那么我们用 alpha
means fully transparent, and alpha 1 means fully opaque and
alpha 为 0 意味着完全透明，alpha 为 1 意味着完全不透明
we can have any number in between. The way get
而我们可以用它们之间的任何值，这样我们就能得到
a transparent color, is take a color you've got, like yellow
一个透明的颜色，如果你要得到一个透明的颜色，你要用你的颜色，比如说这里的黄色
let's say right there, and you send it the message, or
接着你向它传递一个信息
the function, withAlphaComponent. And
或者说一个函数，withAlphaComponent()
it will give you a new color that has that transparency.
这就会返回给你一个有着这个透明度的新的颜色
Now you can draw with that transparency.
接着你画图就可以有透明度了
If you want to draw in you view with transparency,
如果你们画图的时候想带有透明度
though, be very careful. Because,
一定要小心
the system assumes by default that your view only
因为系统默认地认为你的视图是以
draws opaque. It only draws with fully opaque colors.
不透明的方式画的，认为你的视图是完全不透明的
If you actually draw with transparent colors,
如果你实际上以透明的颜色来画图
you have to set a var on the view called opaque to false.
你必须要将你视图里的一个叫做 opaque 的变量设置为 false
Now why does he do this? Well, imagine how much more CPU and
为什么要这么做呢？想想当你带有透明度画图时
GPU intensive it is to draw with transparency because now
会增加多少 CPU 和 GPU 的开销
the views behind you have to be composited with your bits,
因为在这个视图之后的那个视图必须要和前面那个视图拼合
and you know the compositing not cheap, all right?
你们也知道这样拼合是要消耗非常多的资源的，对吧
The GPU got a lot of work to do there, so
GPU 要在这里做许多工作
that's why it says to assume everything is opaque and
这就是它默认所有的视图都是不透明的的原因
that everything overlapping doesn't have to be composited.
这样所有重叠的部分不用去拼合
And, so if you wanna draw with transparency,
如果你们想要带有透明度地画图
which is fine. It's legal.
这是可以的，合法的
It's not that expensive that you would never wanna do it.
它没有那么消耗资源到你完全不会这么做的程度
But just make sure you set this opaque to false.
但要记得将这个 opaque 设置为 false
And you can do this in interface builder.
你可以在 interface builder 中做到这一点
You can click on the view,
你可以点击那个视图
and one of the things in the inspector over there is
而检查器中的其中一个属性就是
whether it's opaque and just turn that off. By the way,
它是否是不透明的，你只需要将它关掉
you can make your entire view transparent, if you want,
还有，如果你想的话，你可以将你整个视图设置为透明的
by setting it alpha,
通过设置视图的 alpha
so views have alpha. That means all your drawing in
也就是说视图也有 alpha，这意味着你所有的画图
there will be somewhat transparent.
都会具有透明度
That's kind of a cool feature. All right,
这是一个挺酷的特性
brief mention about layers. So UIView's drawing mechanism,
现在简单讲讲层(layer)，UIView 的机制
is actually built on another whole system I'm not
实际上是建立在一个另外的系统上的
gonna talk about, called Core Animation. And that's because
我不会讲到它，它叫 Core Animation(核心动画) ，这是因为
everything you do in a view can be animated. Views moving,
你在视图中做的所有事情都是可以被动画化的，视图的移动
transparency happening, all this stuff can be animated and
透明度的改变之类的都是可以被动画化的
there's a whole layer for doing that. And so,
而有一整个层是用来做到这一点的
the UIView, we see a top level API for it, but there's
对于 UIView，我们只看到了它的顶层的 API，但实际上
actually a whole other API for drawing called the CALayer,
它有另外一些用来画图的的 API，叫做 CALayer
Core Animation Layer API.
Core Animation Layer API(核心动画层 API)
And I actually mentioned this in the hints of Assignment 2,
而我实际上在第二次的作业的提示中提到了这个
you've already seen this. There's this var in UIView,
你们已经见过它了，在 UIView 中有一个变量
it's in button because button's a UIView,
在这里是 UIButton 中的变量，因为它也是一个 UIView
called layer, which gives you the layer, the CALayer, that's
这个变量叫做 layer，它回给你那个 CALayer
being used. Now I'm gonna talk all about animation,
它是正在被用的。我应该会在下一周讲到动画
hopefully next week, maybe the week after, and
或者是下下周
we'll get into some of this stuff. But you already know
那时我会深入地讲这些东西，但你们已经从第二次作业中
from Assignment 2 that there's a few really nice vars in
学到了，在 CALayer 中是有一些非常好的变量的
the CALayer like cornerRadius, if you wanna put a rounded
比如说 cornerRadius，你会用它将一个圆角矩形
rect on your view, or the borderWidth and borderColor.
放在你的视图中，或者 borderWidth 和 borderColor
By the way, you notice that the borderColor there was
还有，注意到 borderColor 是一个
a CGColor, not a UIColor.
CGColor，而不是 UIColor
CGColor means it's a Core Graphics color, why is that?
CGColor 意味着他是 Core Graphics(核心图形)的颜色，为什么呢
Well, that's because this whole layer mechanism,
因为这整个层次的机制
Core Animation, is below the UIKit layer, and
Core Animation，是在 UIKit 层下面的
it built on top of the Core Graphics layer. So
而他又是在 Core Graphics 层次上面建立的
it can't really use the UIColor struct
它并不能使用 UIColor
because it's kind of above it in the hierarchy of frameworks
因为 UIColor 是在它的上层的互相依赖的
depending on each other, so use a C, CGColor.
等级层次的，所以它用的是 CGolor
Luckily, UIColor is also above Core Graphics. So it has a var
幸运的是，UIColor 是在 Core Graphics 的上层的，因此它有一个变量
called CGColor, which gives you itself as a CGColor, and
叫做 CGColor，它会将它以 CGColor 的类型返回
I showed all that in the hints of your assignment,
我会在你们的作业的提示中展示给你们
right? Okay, so that's a layer thing, we'll talk about,
这就是层的东西，我们之后会讲到
more about animation later. Let's talk a little bit about
更多的关于动画的东西。现在我们来讲讲
the transparency and how that works, like which views are in
透明度是如何运作的，比如说哪个视图是在
front of which other views, right? If I have a transparent
其他视图前面的，如果我有一个透明的视图
view, and it shows the one behind, which is behind?
它会显示在它后面的视图，那么哪个视图是在后面的
That's all determined by the order of the subviews list.
这是由它们在 subviews 这个数组中的顺序来决定的
Any view that has subviews has an array of them.
所有有子视图的视图都会有一个装着它们的数组
The first thing in that array is the back. And
这个数组中的第一个视图是在最下面的
everything else is one step in front,
而其他的视图都是在它前一个的上面的
the last thing is the one in the very front.
最后一个视图是在最上面的
So if you have multiple subviews of your view and
如果你在你的视图中有多个子视图
they overlap, it's the one in back is the first one in
并且它们相互重叠，那么在最下面的视图
the subviews list. So you can reorder the subviews list and
是被装在这个 subviews 数组的第一个的。你也可以重新
move them. Move the one from the front to the back or
将这个 subviews 数组排序，将第一个视图移动到最后一个
whatever, so you can control that transparency effect.
或者其他什么。这样你就可以控制透明的效果
Also, even if there's no transparency,
如果没有透明度
if the views are on top of each other and
而如果那些视图是一个在一个上面的
they happen to overlap.
而它们又有重叠的部分
A lot of times when we have multiple subviews,
多数时候我们会有多个子视图
they're are all side by side, they don't overlap,
它们都是边挨着边的，但没有重叠
but they could. Oops, they could overlap, and if they
但它们是可以重叠的
did, then that subviews will tell you the order,
如果它们的确是重叠的，那么那个 subviews 数组就会告诉你
which ones are in the front. You can completely
它们哪个在前哪个在后的顺序，你完全可以
hide a view without taking it out of the view hierarchy,
在不把一个视图从视图架构取出的情况下隐藏它
with isHidden. If you say to a view, this is a var on view,
通过使用 isHidden 变量，如果你对一个视图设置
if you say view isHidden equals yes, it will not appear
它的 isHidden，isHidden 是视图的一个变量，将它设置为真
on screen. It'll still be in the view hierarchy,
那么这个视图就不会出现在屏幕上，它仍然存在于视图的架构中
still in the subviews list. It'll still have a superview,
也仍然存在于 subviews 数组中，它仍然会有父视图
but it won't there, and it won't get any gestures either.
但它不会出现在屏幕上，也不会接受任何手势(gesture)
So you won't see its drawing,
你不会看到它被画出来
you won't get any gestures, it'll be hidden. And
当视图被隐藏时，它是不会接受任何手势的
you'll be surprised how common it is to wanna do these.
你会惊讶于这样的需求是有多么普遍
You put a view in the view hierarchy somewhere,
你将一个视图放进视图架构的某处
you hide it, then when some condition is true, it appears,
你接着将它隐藏起来，当某些条件为真时，它才显示
probably animated. Things appear, that's a common way to
可能是动画地显示出来。这是构建交互式 UI
build an interactive UI. All right, so we know how
的普遍的方法。好的我们已经知道
to draw with these arcs. What about drawing text? Well,
如何画这些弧了，那么如何画文字呢
actually text is just some font designer, moveto, lineto,
文字实际上一些字体设计师用 moveto, lineto
curveto, okay. That's all the character, every character in
curveto 等方法创建的。所有的字符都是这样，文字中所有的字符
the text is just a bunch of little moveto, lineto's.
都会一些 moveto, lineto 什么的
Luckily, some font designer somewhere did those all for
幸运的是，在某地的字体设计师已经已经将
you, or that would be incredibly tedious for
那些帮你做好了，不然做这些对你来说会是
you now, wouldn't it? So we wanna be able to draw though
非常无聊的，对吧。那么我们希望能用这些美妙的 moveto
using these wonderful moveto, linetos, which are the glyphs
lineto 来画图，它们是字体中的
in a font. So how do we do that? Well, before I even dive
象形成分。那么我们该怎么做的这一点呢？在我将那之前
into that, remember that UILabel draws text real well.
要记得 UILabel 可以很好地画出文字
And there's no reason you couldn't make a UILabel be
而没有什么阻止你让一个 UILabel
a subview of your view, and thus draw the text that way.
成为你的视图的一个子视图，这样就可以用 UILabel 来画图了
Okay, that's a great way to draw it, because UILabel's got
那是很好地一种画图方法，因为 UILabel 中
all the incredible amount of center text alignment,
有所有的那些文字居中什么的功能
and you can control the color,
你可以控制颜色
you can put an attributed string on that label.
你可以在它里面放一个 NSAttributedString
You've got complete control with that.
你有所有那些功能的控制权
The only thing is you have to make sure that you keep that
唯一要注意的是你要确保你将那个
UILabels frame in the right spot in your subview.
UILabel 的框架放在了你的子视图中的合适的地方
You know, as, it's one of your subviews, so you've gotta make
就是说它是一个你的子视图，因此你要确保
sure its frame is kept in the right space. But
将它的框架放在了正确的地方
that's a great way to draw text, so
那是画文字的非常好的方式
don't forget that. But I will talk to you now about how to
不要忘记了。而我现在要讲讲如何在你的
draw in your draw rect, and use attributed string. Okay,
draw(rect) 中画文字，并使用 NSAttributedString
so you just create AttributedString,
你只需要创建一个 NSAttributedString
and you send it the message draw, and
并且你调用它的 draw 函数
it will draw at the point you say in your current context.
它就会在你传递参数的那个点，在你当前所在的视图画图
So drawing text could not be easier,
画文字简直不能更简单了
you already know how to do an attributed string, so
你知道该如何使用 NSAttributedString
you just create attributed string here.
你只需要创建一个 NSAttributedString
My attributed string doesn't have any attributes here for
为了节省幻灯片的空间，我的 NSAttributedString
slide space issue. But
在这里没有任何属性
you could put your attributes on it, whatever, and
但你的可以为它设置属性
then do draw(at. You can also do draw(in), and it'll draw it
并且调用 draw(at) 你也可以调用 draw(in) 它会
in a rectangle in the upper left corner of the rectangle.
在一个矩形区域从左上角开始画文字
And then you can also get the size of the text by
接着通过直接访问这个 NSAttributedString
just asking the attributed string, what is the width and
的 size 来得到在它的大小，从而得知想将
height necessary to fit this attributed string. So
它装进矩形的最小的宽和高是多少
super easy to draw text in your draw rect,
在你的 draw(rect) 画文字是非常简单的
you just use AttributedString. Now I wanted to take a little
你只需要用到 NSAttributedString。现在我想画一点时间
time here about AttributedString and
来讲讲 NSAttributedString
circle back to what I said about it before.
并且回到我以前将的东西
Remember I talked about how NSAttributedString is
还记得我之前讲 NSAttributedString 说他是
an old objective thing, and it uses NSString and then,
一个老的 Objective-C 的东西，并且它使用 NSString
we're using String? And String uses kind of a different
而我们正在使用 String，而 String 使用有一点不同的
encoding for Unicode characters and sometimes
Unicode 字符编码，而有时
mapping between NSString and String. The indexing is
我们会在 NSString 和 String 中互相映射
different because we got wacky characters like emoji,
它们的下标索引是不同的，因为我们会有奇怪的字符，像 emoji
that are actually multiple Unicodes,
它们实际上是多个 Unicode 字符
ugh, that whole mess, you remember that? Well,
真是乱得一团糟，你记得吗
I'm gonna tell you a little bit how to get around that.
我会给你们讲讲如何绕过那一点
You don't need it, you didn't need it for Assignment 2,
你现在用不上，你在作业 2 中也用不上
you won't need it for
你在作业 3 中
Assignment 3. Maybe I'll ask you to do for
也用不上，可能我会让你们在
Assignment 5. But if I do wanna set attributes just on
作业 5 中用上。当我想要在我的 NSAttributedString 中
certain characters in my AttributedString, and
的特定字符上设置属性时
it's a String, not a NSString, how do I do it?
它们是一个 String，而不是 NSString，我该怎么做呢
Well, the answer is, this class right here, NSRange. So
答案是，用在这里的这个类，NSRange
NSRange is the way you specify a range into an NSString.
NSRange 是你将一个 range 转换成 NSString 的方法
Okay, so this is an old Objective-C way of doing
这是一个老的 Objective-C 的处理 range 的方法
a range. In our world, we do Range.
在我们的这里，我们用 Range
That's how we index into a string, right,
这是我们索引 String 的方法
because we know the strings are indexed by String.Index
因为我们知道 String 是由 String.Index
not by int. So we have this totally different thing,
来索引的，而不是 Int，我们现在有这个完全不同的东西
Range. And here AttributedString wants to do
Range 而这里 NSAttributedString 想要
an NSRange of int because NSString was indexed by init.
一个 Int 型的 NSRange，因为 NSString 是以 Int 索引的
Okay, so how do we get from range of String.Index to
那么我们如何从 String.Index 的 range 得到
NSRange of an int that matches, okay, so
相对应的 Int 的 NSRange 呢
that the NSAttributedString matches our string. Well,
这样 NSAttributedString 就能对应我们的 String
we do it with NSRange, we do it with this right here.
我们用 NSRange 来做到，我们用在这里的代码
This is NSRange initializer, you see it,
这是 NSRange 的初始化函数
NSRange initializer. It takes this firstWordRange,
这个NSRange 初始化函数接受这个 firstWordRange
which is an Swift range of string.index. You see it goes
为参数，它是一个 Swift 的 String.Index 的 range
from startIndex here over to indexOf, so it's a range. It's
你看这有 startIndex 到 indexOf，所以它是一个 range
got the little ..< which is our nice range syntax there.
它有我们的 range 的语法，那个 ..<
So it takes a range and it converts it into an NSRange,
所以这个初始化函数接受一个 range 并且将它转化为 NSRange
but it needs to know the string that that string,
但它需要知道它要转化的 String
those string.indexes are into, right?
就是那些 String.Index 索引的那个 String
So the combination of knowing the string and
那么当它同时知道那个 String
the string.index range. It can crunch on that and change it
和 String.Index 的 range 时，它就可以
into an NSRange that will work in an NSAttributedString.
将它转化可以用于 NSAttributedString 的 NSRange，
So that's the magic. NSRange,
这就是那个技巧，NSRange
use the initializer that takes a range of string.index and
用这个接受 一个 String.Index 的 range 和 一个 String
a string. It'll give you back NSRange.
的初始化函数，它会返回一个 NSRange
Now you can call methods like in AttributedString,
那么接着你就可以调用 NSAttributedString 中的函数了
like addAttribute, which adds a single attribute at
比如说 addAttribute 它会在指定的字符区间
a certain range of characters. Look at the argument, range,
添加一个属性，看到它的参数
nsrange, now you have an nsrange to give it. All right,
range:NSRange 现在你就有一个可以传给它的 NSRange 了
fonts. Okay, fonts incredibly important in iOS. I cannot
好的，字体是 iOS 中非常重要的一部分
overstate how important fonts are to the look and
我怎样也不会夸大字体对 iOS 的外观
feel of iOS. These are, I think are iOS 10 screenshots,
与体验的作用。这些是 iOS 10 的屏幕截图
and iOS 11 things have changed slightly, but not too much.
而 iOS 11 改变了一点，不是很多
But even in these screenshots you can see how important
但在这些屏幕截图中你也可以看出字体是多么的重要
fonts is. They really make a difference to how your UI
它们真的让你的 UI
looks. So you have to pick the right font.
看起来不同了。因此你要选择合适的字体
So how do we pick fonts? Well, in iOS,
我们应当如何选择字体？在 iOS 中
the most important concept with font is preferred fonts.
字体的最重要的一个概念是首选字体(preferred fonts)
There are about ten categories of fonts like body fonts,
我们有大约 10 种字体的种类，比如说 body fonts(主字体)
headline fonts, caption fonts, footnote fonts.
headline fonts(标题字体)，, caption fonts(字幕字体), footnote fonts(脚注字体)
So there's these kinds of fonts, and
我们有这些字体类型
you need to pick one of those preferred fonts for
而你需要为你的文字所在的环境
whatever environment you're text is in. If you're showing
选择那些首选字体的其中一种
main information then it's probably the body font.
如果你在展示主要信息，你可能会选 body font
If it's a little caption of an image, you're gonna use to
如果那是一张图片的说明，那么你可能会选 caption font
caption font. Okay, so you got to pick the right font and
所以你要选择并使用正确的字体
use it. Now this is really easy to do Interface Builder.
这在 interface builder 中是很容易做的
You just pick your label, or button, or text field, or
你只用选中你的 UILabel，或者 UIButton 或者 UITextField
whatever you're doing, and you go to inspector, and
或者其他你在用的，接着你去检查器
where it says font, instead of using system font, which is
找到字体属性，不要选择我们一直使用的
what we've always chosen, because I haven't talked to
系统字体，因为我们之前还没有给你们讲过
you about preferred font, you choose one of these things,
首选字体，你从以下一些字体中选一种
body font, caption font, footnote font, etc.
body font, caption font, footnote font，之类的
In your code you could do the same thing, and
你可以在你的代码中做到同样的事
you do that using this static i.e class type method
你用这个静态的，也就是定义在类上的函数
in UI font, called preferred font for text style, and
这个在 UIFont 中叫做 preferredFont(forTextStyle) 的函数
that text style is headline, body, footnote,
而 text style 就是 headline，body，footnote
whatever. This will give you back a UI font that you
之类的。这会返回给你一个 UIFont
can put in your NSAttributedString dictionary.
你可以将它用在你的 NSAttributedString 的字典中
One of the keys in there is the font, and you can use this
它其中的一个键是字体，接着你可以将这个
as the font, when you're drawing text in your drawRect.
字体用在 draw(rect) 中画文字的时候
Now one thing to be concerned about here is that the size of
这里值得考虑的一件事是，这个字体的
this font is variable. But you get old people like,
大小是一个变量，对于想我一样的老年人来说
okay, we're starting to hold our phones like this,
我们渐渐开始这样拿着手机
as the years go by, cuz our eyes are giving up, so
随着时间流逝，我们的眼睛越来越差了
we like the fonts big. Then we can hold it all closer and
所以我们想大的字体，这样我们就可以将手机拿近
see our fonts. Well, the way we do that is we go into our
来看字了。
settings on our phone, and one of the settings under general
there is accessibility, and we can say larger text, and
we move the little slider, and
now all the fonts get bigger in all the apps, but
only the apps that play this game right, and
use preferred fonts. So you wanna be one of those apps,
otherwise, you're gonna lose the older folk from
your demographic,
of your people buying your app. So it's important to make
sure that your UI also works when fonts get bigger and
smaller, and the number one way to do that, auto layout.
You know that auto layout where you put constraints,
pin things to the edges. You wanna use good auto layout so
as fonts get bigger, and the text field gets bigger, other
things push out of the way and it uses the screen real estate
properly. So you've only seen a little bit of auto layout.
I'm gonna show you more auto layout at start of Wednesday's
lecture. You're gonna see more and
more as the quarter goes by, but
that's a good way to make it work. Now what if you
either wanna use some other font, some special font that's
something that's maybe part of your marketing or whatever, or
you want it to be bigger, or smaller I guess,
than the standard size font that comes with a certain
prefered font. Okay, well, UIFont does have a way to
create a font by name like if you want Helvetica 36 point,
you can say UIFont(name: "Helvetica", size: 36.0), and
there's also a class called UIFontDescriptor.
Has a lot of cool ways where you can take a font and
say give me the Bold version of this,
give me the Italic version, okay all of that stuff. So
you can get your font this way. But if you do your fonts
this way, you still want, when I go into my setting and
make my font bigger, you want your font to get bigger, and
look what font size this is, 36. It's fixed.
So I need to somehow scale this font up
if the user has put their slider to bigger, and
the way you do that is with UIFontMetrics. So you create
a UIFontMetrics object for the text style body, footnote,
caption, whatever, and then it has very cool method called
scaledFont, and you give it a font, like Helvetica 36,
and it will give you back a new font, Helvetica 42, maybe.
It's scaled based on what the user said. Okay, don't skip
this step, otherwise, if you use a custom font,
when people move that slider, your app's not gonna work, and
people are gonna be like, I hate that app.
I can't see any of the text and it's too small.
There are also system fonts. We use those so far in our
concentration demo. That's only for things like button
titles, and stuff like that, that's not for user content,
stuff that the user has generated, or requested, or
something like that. Thos are preferred fonts.
System fonts are just like buttons, things like that.
What about images? We know how to draw lines and arcs.
We know how to draw text.
What about drawing images? Just like UILabel for text,
there's another one called UIImageView,
which lets you add an image as a subview. So you could use
that to draw an image in your view if you want it,
just do it as a subview. But if you wanna draw an image
in your drawRect, you can do that too.
You need a UIImage object. A UIImage represents an image,
jpg, gif, whatever kind of image, it represents an image.
Now, how do you get an image? There's a bunch of ways to do
it. One way is to drag the jpg file, or whatever, into that
Assets.xcassets file. Remember when we're doing our demo,
and I put some things off in supporting files?
One of the things I threw in there was the place where
the app icon was. Well, you can drag other images in
there, and along the left hand side will be all the names
of them, and then you can call this method right here,
UIImage named whatever, and it'll go look in that assets
thing, and find an image with that name.
Now, this is a failable initializer.
It can return nil, and that's because it might not find
that particular image in there. So you have to say
usually if let to do that. How else can you get an image?
Well, you can get one from the file system.
You've got a jpg in the file system.
I hadn't told you how to access the file system, so
you're not gonna be doing that. I'll show you later.
You can also get it if you have a bag of bits that you
got over the Internet. The data that has a bags of bits
with jpg data in there. UIImage knows how to look in
that bag of bits and figure out if it's an image.
You can even use this global function,
UIGraphicsBeginImageContext, and then draw arcs and
lines, and it'll capture it as an image. So
you can even draw a custom image if you want. So anyway,
you do one of these things, and
now you have a UIImage in your hand that represents the image
you wanna draw. How do you draw it?
Exactly the same as NS attributed string, you just
use draw(at), which will draw the image with its upper-left
corner at that point, but you also can do draw(in rect, and
it'll scale the image to fit in that rect.
So that's a cool way to scale your image up and down, and
you can do drawAsPattern which will tally your image
repeatedly, repeat you image to fill the rectangle.
Super easy to draw images as well.
All right, let's talk about your bounds changing.
I've got my draw rect. It draw beautifully, but now my bounds
changed, and when will this happen? Well, number one way,
your device got rotated. They were looking at you in
portrait, they rotate you. Now you also went from this tall,
thin view, now you're this wide, very short view, okay,
your bounds have completely changed.
You went from a width of maybe 200 to a width of maybe 700,
and from a height of maybe 3 or 400 to a height of 150 or
200, so that's a major change.
You're gonna have to really redraw all of your stuff,
usually. Unfortunately, that's not the default. In iOS,
when you're bounds change like that, it does not redraw you,
believe or not. It takes all your bits And squishes them.
So looks absolutely terrible most of the time.
To smashes a bit, squishes them down,
stretches them out to fit your new bounds.
Which you almost never want that. So how is that control?
That's control with a var in UIView called contentMode.
Okay, and the contentMode's just basically saying,
what kind of content do I have? Do I have the kind of
content that can be squished and scrunched like that, and
still look good? Or do I have the kind of content where I
have to be redrawn when my balance changes?
So, the three different categories of contentModes.
One is, keep my bits, okay, don't redraw me, but just move
my bits, unscaled, to a new position, upper left, top,
lower right, keep it in the center, whatever.
This one not almost never get used. Then they're scaling
the bits which is scaleToFill as the default where it just
scrunches the bits to fit in the new space. It doesn't even
respect the aspect ratio. But you could set the contentMode
to scores the bit but keep the aspect ratio the same size so
that a face doesn't go from, you know, an over as way to
a tall over or whatever. But the one you guys probably
are gonna want most of the time is ContentMode redraw.
And what that means is, when my bounds change,
call my draw Rect and let me draw myself again, and
that's probably what you want.
Could you draw rect knows what your bounds are and
when it gets called, it can draw something appropriate for
the bounds you read. So like in your homework, for example,
well maybe your homework is not a great example because
probably, the big views that are changing bound
it's your subviews that you are gonna want to lay out,
which I will talk about again. But if you did have a thing
where you are drawing something in a view,
like maybe we are doing our cards and concentration. And
we always want them, to be a certain aspect ratio,
whatever, we could redraw, in our draw Rect or whatever,
it's probably not a great example.
In fact, let's go on to the next example which is,
what happens if I have subviews and
my bounds change? Cuz this is gonna happen in your homework.
You're gonna have some views, you're just gonna have
a subview which is a lot of cards, your set cards. Because
in assignment three, now there's no limit on the number
of cards that can appear on screen, right?
In assignment two, we limited to like 24 cards as the most.
Now no limit, so you're always adding more cards. So,
you're gonna have to use, put them as subviews of some view.
You can't stack view anymore, in other words.
So what happens when your bounds change there?
Well, when your bounds change,
you're gonna get sent this message layoutSubviews.
And that's an opportunity for you to go reset the frames by
just changing the frame var on all of your subviews, okay.
So, you're all, if you have subviews,
you're almost always gonna implement this method.
And don't forget to call super to do it. Now, what's the one
time when you're not gonna implement this method?
Is if you have subviews and you have autolayout on those
subviews, okay. If you have autolayout on your subviews,
then the Autolayout constrains will determine where
the new frames are, okay. So this would only be for
views where you're not using autolayout.
that might be true of your assignment three,
whatever view contains your card, probably not gonna use
autolayout. It will be almost impossible to write
constraints that would work for
laying out an arbitrary number of cards in arbitrary bounds,
okay. You're probably gonna wanna do that in code. Okay,
so when your bounds change, you've got two different
things to think about. If you have any subviews,
layout subviews or autolayout. And if you draw something,
then you've gotta think about your content mode on whether
you wanna be asked to redraw. Okay, so that's it for
the slides today, I'm gonna into demo here.
The demo I'm gonna do is a playing card. So this is gonna
be a new app, and it's just gonna draw a playing card,
you know, like jack of clubs, six of hearts, whatever,
it's gonna draw that card. We're gonna draw that custom,
by ourselves. And today, all I am gonna do in the demo is
the model of that MVC that draws the playing card, which
is gonna be a playing card and a deck of playing cards.
And the reason I'm gonna do that is I wanna show you enum.
You haven't grab a chance to see me demo enum. So
we're gonna use enums in our implementation of our model.
On Wednesday, I'll continue with the drawing part of this
demo or I'm gonna draw this playing card.
And then I'll do some slides on multitouch and
then we'll add some multitouch to the playing cards, swiping
to go to the next card, we'll do tapping the flip the card
over, that kind of stuff. Okay, your assignment two
of course is due on Wednesday as you know.
Assignment three will be assigned on Wednesday.
It's just to make your set game custom cards, okay,
drawn with a custom view,
that's what assignment three is basically about. We don't
have a Friday section again this week, unfortunately,
due to some scheduling conflicts, but
next Friday we will and it'll be on source code management.
Okay, let's go create a new app here.
Okay, so I'm just gonna go over here, use this same
splash screen but I gonna say create a new Xcode project,
this has nothing to do with concentration here.
As always with the single view app,
I'm gonna call this app PlayingCard.
That's what it does to show it's a PlayingCard.
We're not doing any database, we're not doing testing yet.
We're gonna put in the same place I put concentration,
we're not doing source code control yet,
although like I'm saying next Friday,
we'll learn about that. Here's my project,
now this time I'm gonna keep my xcassets,
right, here's my xcassets where my AppIcon is here.
I'm gonna keep that because I'm gonna use some images for
the face cards. So you can see how to draw images there.
But I'm not gonna use my launch screen or
my app delegate here. So I'm just gonna put them again in
supporting files. I just like to get them out of the way so
they don't really kind of demand my attention.
Now, before I even go here and build my UI for
my playing card thing, we're gonna go do our model first.
So we're not gonna do any UI to start,
we're gonna do model first. So how do we create model files?
Remember, File > New > File, and we pick this one right
here, Swift File which is a non-UI, right, a UI
independent thing. And when we do that, we ask for the name,
so let's first start by doing a playing card. Okay, now on
my model, it's just gonna be a deck of playing cards.
So these are gonna be UI independent representations
of playing cards, a deck of that. So
we'll start with the playing cards itself and
then we'll do the deck. So here it is right here,
import Foundation, I'm just gonna have it via struct,
there's really no reason for it to be a reference type. And
it's going to be a playing card. Now,
a playing card is made of what? Well, it's got a suit,
which I'm gonna have some type for that, and it's got a rank.
Right, that's all there is in a playing card, suit and rank.
So how are we gonna represent suit and rank?
Well, of course, because I wanted to show you enum,
l'm gonna do it with an enum. So, let's create an enum for
the Suit. And then we're also gonna create another enum for
the Rank. Now let's talk about how we would do this.
Now, Suit is probably the world's simplest enum, right?
It's the case, it could be spades, or it's hearts, or
it's diamonds, or it's clubs, that's it.
This is probably enough right here. That's really all
we need to do for an enum. I'm gonna take this opportunity
to teach you a little bit about enum that
I didn't mention even in the slides.
But it was in your homework reading, so hopefully you got
this which is raw values. What are raw values in an enum?
Well, it turns out that you can associate a fixed
constant raw value for every one of your cases.
Okay, now, Swift will even do some of this automatically.
For example, if I make my raw value type which I specify by
just saying, colon type, after enum, by making being int then
it will automatically make this one's raw value be 0.
And it's gonna make this one's raw value be 1, etc.
Okay, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5. So, it just goes in order,
the lexical order which appears in the file. You can
also make your raw value be a string, for example.
And if I do that, Swift will automatically make this one be
spades, this one will be hearts, this will be diamonds.
Another words, it makes the raw value be A string version
of the case. Now, why would you ever want raw values?
Well, to be honest, I think a lot of the raw values support
backwards compatibility because in Objective-C enums
were essentially ints, right? Zero, one, two, three, four,
five. So raw values it's like raw value int. But
you could imagine, it might be interesting if there is some
piece of data that it makes sense to associate with all
the cases. And again it has to be fixed, and constant, and
unique. For all the cases but still you could imagine that.
For example, I kinda saw that maybe this suit raw,
this might be a good one. If I made the raw value be string,
maybe having the Unicode character that represents
the suit. Kind of be associated with every case,
might be valuable. Now, how can you use raw value?
Two ways, one, you can create a suit by providing the raw
value. And it looks just like an initializer on suits,
suit open parenthesis raw value, that's how you do it.
And you give it like a heart symbol there, and it will give
it back. Now that's a failable initializer cuz you might give
it a string like x, that's not one of these four strings. And
you can go the other way as well.
You can, if you have a suit, like suit.spades, you can say,
what is the raw value? And
you can get this string so that might be useful too.
We don't really care about that in this demo but
I just wanted to show you about this raw value business.
All right, let's go down to Rank. Now, honestly,
if I were doing Rank, it would look like this, case ace,
case two, case three, all the way up to case jack,
case queen, case king. This is what now,
all the ones in between. That's what I would do.
But I'm not gonna do it this way cuz I wanna
show you associated data. This is mostly for demo purposes,
I would probably just do it as these 13 things.
That was probably the best representation for a rank. But
instead, I'm gonna do it with associated data and so
I'm gonna have case ace, then I'm also
gonna have a case face, which is a face card.
And it's gonna have an associated value,
which is a string, which is either J, Q, or K. So there's
gonna be a face card that's either jack, queen or king.
Terrible representation,
at the very least this should be another enum,
not a string which can be anything. It's kinda silly,
but anyway. And then I'm also gonna have case numeric, okay,
for 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10. And it's gonna have,
of course, associated data int. Now, I could put in
here like pips count, a pip by the way is one of these,
a pip on a card is just one of these things. So a numeric
card has 2 pips on it, 2 has 2 pips, 3 has 3 pips and so on.
So I could put pipsCount here as documentation. But you know
what, you actually don't wanna do that if it's completely
obvious what this would be. And if I had a numeric rank,
it's completely obvious that this is the number, so I do
not need that. Now, it's not very obvious what this is but
as I already told you, this is a bad representation anyway.
But I just wanna show you what it looks like to
get the associated data out of here and use it, etc.
For example, rank is an enum, it can have funcs,
I could have funcs and vars on here. So I'm gonna have a var
called order which is an int, which is gonna return the,
which position the rank is in the order. So
I'm gonna switch on myself and if I am an ace, I'm gonna
return 1 cuz that's the first, that's card number 1,
right? If I am a numeric, then I'm going to get my
number of pips. And I'm gonna return the number of pips.
Cuz if I'm an numeric card, then however many pips I have,
that's my number. And then for face,
I'm gonna say case .face, and I'm gonna, whoops,
get the kind, Q or J, or K. Now, I'v got the kind,
I guess I could say, I'm gonna go to the next line and
say, if the kind equals J, then return 11. And
then I guess I could go else if the kind. Okay, but I'm,
this is getting terrible. This is gonna be ugly, awful code.
But turns out there's a lot better way to do all this
which is to go here and say. If it's face where I get
the kind where kind equals J, then return 11.
So this stuff with switch is actually a pattern matching
language, which you can go and learn about.
But one of the things it's able to do is where.
Where it can kind of narrow this down a little bit.
So now I could do that for all three here, the Q and
the king, and return. That's why you can see
why I use this terrible string representations, so
I can show you where. Now, notice when I do this,
I still get this complaint, switch must be exhaustive.
And it's like, what? Look I do ace, I do numeric,
I do face, how come it's not exhaustive?
Well, because where makes it so
these are not counting every possible combination of where.
It could be, the kind could be something else. So, of course,
I have to add here a default break, or
actually I have to return something, so I'll return 0.
This is also bad design. This probably wants to return nil,
and this wants to be an optional. That would be better
design, I'm not gonna do it that way. But just so
you know, that's bad. I could also have static vars here,
maybe I have a static var, which is all the ranks which
returns an array of every single possible rank.
And I'm gonna have to kind of build that up cuz I have all
these weird data structure here. So I'll create something
called allRanks which could be a type array of ranks. And
let's start it out with and ace, notice here by the way
that I have to type this side here. It can't really
deduce this. If I took this away right here, let's get
these other warnings off here, I'll return them allRanks.
If I took this typing right here, this static typing away,
I'm gonna get an error that it can't infer this type.
And that's because there might be another enum that has
a case of .ace. So how does it know the,
which array of enums this is? That's why it's saying type
expression is ambiguous without more context. So
I can add more context by putting that type.
I could also say rank.ace, that would add more context.
And now it knows it's an array of ranks. So
now let's also do for pips in 2...10, remember dot, dot,
dot without the less than means including the 10. And
now I can say, allRanks.append, Rank.numeric
with that pips. So now I've added all my numeric ones, and
then maybe for the thing, face card ones I'll
just say allRanks plus equals an array that has rank.face,
where the kind is a J. And then I'll just copy and
paste, copy, oops, paste, copy, paste and
we'll do the Q and the king. By the way, if I do this,
I only really need to put this Rank dot on the first one and
it can infer the rest of them.
Dots though means dots. So I don't need rank dot, because
it figured out pretty quick this is an array of ranks.
These are all ranks, so it works. I could do the same all
thing up here by the way, too. I could have a static var all.
I make it static because I'm getting all of them here.
I'm not talking about a specific one so
I want them all. So this would be,
we'll do the same thing here. A rank of suit.spades,
.hearts, .diamonds, and .clubs,
oops, hello .clubs. So this is kind of nice to have
this static bar which gives me all the suits, all the ranks.
That's gonna make it a lot easier actually to create our
playing card deck so let's do that. So we've got this nice
representation, not so nice, but somewhat nice,
representation of a playing card. Let's go ahead and
make a deck, so I'm gonna make a New File. A new thing
here it's gonna be a PlayingCardDeck.
Here it is, struct also no reason for not to be
PlayingCardDeck. And, what do I wanna playing card deck.
Well, of course I'm gonna need a var which is
the cards in the deck. Right, so
I'm just gonna make that V an array of playing card,
probably want this to be private set. Okay,
where I control the cards because it's gonna be start up
being a full deck. And then I probably want some function,
like draw which grabs a PlayingCard out of there. So
that's how you take a playing card out of the deck. So
how would I implement drawing the card out of there? Well,
I'm just gonna say, let's see what I remember,
I think I used something from Concentration to do this.
Check I did. Yeah, I did. Okay, so here,
I'm just gonna see if I have any cards.
Then I'm going to return cards.remove at: hover many
cards I have .count.arc4random. So,
I need to go over to Concentration.
Here's concentration down at the bottom here.
We have arc4random. So I'm just gonna grab that out
of here. Put that in here, so I can use arc4random there,
if I don't have any cards left then I'm gonna return nil, so
I better make this draw our return an optional playing
card. Okay, so that way people can't add more
cards to my deck I just start out with a full deck.
Okay, I get start out with a full deck so
I better have an init that does that, init is really easy
to write given our nice plain card structure, sorry,
this warning here, cannot use mutating member on immutable
thing, everybody knows why that is. This is a struct,
it's a value type, this mutated by removing a card,
so we have to say this is a mutating mark,
another good example doing that. All right, so
here I'm just gonna go through all my suits for
suit in Suit.all, and for rank in Rank.all, okay,
then now all these alls that we did, but of course look
where I put suit, if you look at PlayingCard over here, I
put suit inside Playingcards. See I declared it inside,
so Swift allows you to nest types, put types in other
side. Which makes perfect sense here, because Suit
only makes sense in the context of the PlayingCards,
it just makes perfect sense. But it does change the name of
the Suit, it's no longer called suit,
it's called PlayingCard.Suit. Playing Card.Suit and
this is PlayingCard.Rank, PlayingCard.Rank.
So nesting just changes the names of things and
the accessibility can do private and
stuff like that you might not be able to see it. So now that
I have that I can just have my cards append a playing card,
now PlayingCard since it is a struct is going to get this
automatic initializer, you see it right there, so
I'll double click on this to get that. And
the Suit is just gonna be the Suit that I'm for in-ing and
the rank is the rank I'm for in-ing.
So now you can also see the nice context here and
the nice syntax of for
in when this is an array. These are arrays.
We're just going through each element of the array, right.
Remember that these are arrays right here? See,
this is an array for Suits. This is an array that we made
for Ranks. All right. So that's it. Now, last thing I'm
gonna do here is just print out some cards in my deck to
make sure it's working. Kind of a cool place to put testing
code is back in your View Controller. Okay, if you look
at your View Controller you got this two frame methods.
I'm gonna get rid of that one.
But I'm gonna keep this one which was mentioned in your
homework. This is, viewDidLoad is a great place to like
initialize your View Controller. And
also just put like debugging code, checking things out,
things like that. So, here I could do for example,
let's just print out 10 random cards. I'm gonna say for
under bar, cuz I really didn't care about the index,
in 1...10 cuz I want 10 cards. I'm just going to let card
equal a playing card deck, so I need a playing card deck,
var deck = PlayingCardDeck. So I'm just
gonna let the card = deck.draw.
Now, this is going to be an optional playing card right
here, right? Optional playing card because the deck might be
empty, so let's go and say if let, although I probably could
put exclamation point cuz I'm only grabbing 10 cards.
I know there's 52 cards in a deck, but we'll do if. And
now I'm just gonna print this card out. And
I can print a card by using this backslash parenthesis.
Swift knows how to print out things that have,
we'll see what it tries to print out when we,
when we do this here. So let's try that and see what happens.
So I have no UI's, so this could be a blank UI but
it's gonna print this stuff out on my console so I really
only need to just look at my console here, Right, so
there's my thing here, so here it is printing it out,and
it prints out 10 random cards, kind, ugly looking right here,
it prints out all the vars and etc. One thing that's really
cool that I don't have time to show unfortunately,
cuz we've already gone over but I'll just mention it,
is that you can make it so that something prints out
really nice when it's got that parenthesis,
backslash parenthesis, by making it implement the custom
string convertible protocol. So if we made playing card
implement custom string protocol,
the only thing that's in that if we do fix it,
we'll see what it is, is this var description and
you can return, like here I could return for example
a combination of the Rank and the Suit, and then I can go
make custom string convertible for Rank and Suit down here.
Comma CustomStringConvertible. Implement the description in
there as well. Okay, which I'm trying to do, so
we will go here, we will put description, we will go here,
we will put the description, and we would implement these
two vars, and then when we print out, it would print this
nice string with two nice strings with that.
Now, we wouldn't get all that really verbose printing out.
So CustomStringConvertible is a nice protocol to implement
if you want things to print nice in the console. Okay, so
that's it. I will see you on Wednesday.
We will dive into doing the M or the V and C part,
which is to draw a playing card.
And we'll learn all of that custom views and
all that, I know there is more to touch after that.
See you then. >> For
more, please visit us at stanford.edu.
>> 更多课程详见 stanford.edu